<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" /><updated>2023-03-02T13:25:22+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Batuhan’s Blog</title><subtitle>The Batuhan's Blog</subtitle><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>bthyilmaz@outlook.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">I’m back on Blogging</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/im-back-on-blogging/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I’m back on Blogging" /><published>2023-02-23T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-02-23T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/im-back-on-blogging</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/im-back-on-blogging/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone I’m Batuhan and today I can’t be more happier becouse I’ll be able to start on blogging again. So soo much thing happened in the past, huge earthquakes fallen buildings restarting my life from scratch and etc …
What matters most is me and my family is still alive and today I decided to start blogging again. I had a backup of that website on a hidden Codeberg repo and thanks to that I’m able to restart hosting this website. 
I’m just writing this tiny post to inform you guys that I’m perfectly fine and just busy with recreating my life and other stuff. I want to say thank you for anyone supports Turkey on this disaster and helps us. Without any further words. Until next time guys!</p>

<h2 id="thank-you">Thank You!</h2>
<p>Batuhan Yılmaz - 23.02.2023 - 6/100</p>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yaşar Yılmaz</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello everyone I’m Batuhan and today I can’t be more happier becouse I’ll be able to start on blogging again. So soo much thing happened in the past, huge earthquakes fallen buildings restarting my life from scratch and etc … What matters most is me and my family is still alive and today I decided to start blogging again. I had a backup of that website on a hidden Codeberg repo and thanks to that I’m able to restart hosting this website. I’m just writing this tiny post to inform you guys that I’m perfectly fine and just busy with recreating my life and other stuff. I want to say thank you for anyone supports Turkey on this disaster and helps us. Without any further words. Until next time guys!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Adding RSS feeds from other blogs to end of my posts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/adding-rss-feeds-from-other-blogs-to-end-of-my-posts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Adding RSS feeds from other blogs to end of my posts" /><published>2023-01-26T21:00:11+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-26T21:00:11+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/adding-rss-feeds-from-other-blogs-to-end-of-my-posts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/adding-rss-feeds-from-other-blogs-to-end-of-my-posts/"><![CDATA[<p>Hey guys I’m Batuhan and at the second post of this day I’m gonna talk about how I added latest posts from the RSS feeds I follow to my blog.</p>

<p><img src="https://archive.thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/Media/Images/blog/Screenshot%202023-01-26%20at%2023.58.40.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Like that. 
So to do that I used a script named openring to do that. openring is a simple script that creates webrings using the RSS feeds. It fetches the RSS feeds that you’ve provided and creates an html file that you can place  into includes folder. So let’s go a step by step on how you can do that.</p>

<h3 id="1--install-go">1 ) Install go</h3>

<p>So this script has written in go and before start using it you have to compile it using go. I’m currently on macOS and gonna show the macOS way. But if you’re on a different OS than me you can go to https://go.dev/dl/ page and download the right binary for your OS. 
I’m going to use the macPorts to install the go into my system. To install it use the command <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">sudo port install go</code> and wait for it. After that you can get into step 2.</p>

<h3 id="2--clone-openring-and-build-it">2 ) Clone openring and build it</h3>

<p>Now open your terminal again and clone the openring using the command down below.</p>
<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>git clone https://git.sr.ht/~sircmpwn/openring &amp;&amp; cd openring
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>After that command is done, run the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">go build</code> command and wait for it. After it’s done, you can continue to step 3.</p>

<h3 id="3--use-the-openring">3 ) Use the openring</h3>

<p>And here is the step that we’re going to use the openring. Using it is very simple.</p>

<p><img src="https://archive.thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/Media/Images/blog/Screenshot%202023-01-27%20at%2000.21.39.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Now in there you can see a file named in.html. This file is our template, you can edit this file for your site’s needs and have a much better look that fits into your site. Now we’re going to create a file named out.html that includes our posts using the openring. To create that file you can use the command I put down below.</p>
<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>openring \
-s https://www.joelchrono12.xyz/feed.xml \ 
-s https://andy-bell.co.uk/feed \ 
-s https://kevquirk.com/feed.xml \
&lt; in.html \
&gt; out.html 
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>This command takes the in.html, adds 3 sources I placed and outputs it as the out.html. You can change these feeds as you like these are the ones that I’ve added to my site.</p>

<p>So now it’s time to switch into jekyll part.</p>

<p>Now in order to add our webring to our Jekyll blog. This part is really simple. 
So now place the out.html file that you just created into _includes folder inside your jekyll blog and after that go to your _layouts folder and open the post.html file.  After that place the
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">% include out.html %</code> line under the main tag.</p>

<p><img src="https://archive.thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/Media/Images/blog/Screenshot%202023-01-27%20at%2000.42.42.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Like in that picture. And you’re done.</p>

<p>I hope this post helps to everyone who wants to use openring on their own blog site. I wrote that blogpost while I’m so sleepy and I’m sorry for any mistakes I had.</p>

<h2 id="thank-you">Thank You!</h2>

<p>Batuhan Yılmaz - 27.01.2023 - 5/100</p>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>bthyilmaz@outlook.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey guys I’m Batuhan and at the second post of this day I’m gonna talk about how I added latest posts from the RSS feeds I follow to my blog.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">It’s time for personal blogs to make a comeback</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/its-time-for-personal-blogs-to-make-a-comeback/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="It’s time for personal blogs to make a comeback" /><published>2023-01-26T15:32:11+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-26T15:32:11+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/its-time-for-personal-blogs-to-make-a-comeback</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/its-time-for-personal-blogs-to-make-a-comeback/"><![CDATA[<p>Hey guys I’m Batuhan and todays blogpost I’m going to talk about why personal blogging should make a comeback. Actually I had been considering to write a blogpost on that topic for some time. When I came across with The Verge’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23513418/bring-back-personal-blogging">this post</a> about bringing the blogging back and its importance for the internet. I decided to write my troughs on that.</p>

<p>The post from The Verge mostly talks about how it was before the introduction of the Web 2.0 and how people were connected to each other with these blogs. I won’t gonna talk about that on this post becouse I was born in 2005 and my first internet usage was at the 2012. In these days the only place I knew was the Youtube and the Facebook. And becouse of that I don’t know or remember anything from that era. But I think that having a personal blog is a much better for sharing your story or your creations and here is my reasons for that.</p>

<h2 id="1--youre-the-only-owner-of-your-content">1 ) You’re the only owner of your content</h2>

<p>So when you create your blog site using simple tools like <a href="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</a> or <a href="https://jekyllrb.com">Jekyll</a> and host it on <a href="https://pages.github.com">Github Pages</a> or <a href="https://codeberg.page">Codeberg Pages</a>, you’re the owner. You’re completely free with your content, and no one other than you has any control over it. On platforms like Twitter, you’re not actually the owner of your account or the content you share. When something happens, it could get deleted for some “reasons,” and recovering that deleted content could be a huge pain.</p>

<h2 id="2--its-better-than-micro-blogging-for-sharing-content">2 ) It’s better than Micro blogging for sharing content</h2>

<p>With the intoduction of the Twitter in 2006, people met with a new term named micro blogging. It had less characters than a typical blogpost and aimed for sharing tiny things like a small update on your project or sharing what you’re doing on that exact moment. Not suitable for sharing articles or stories. Yes there is people sharing chains of tweets to tell big stories but that actually makes reading that story of the article less readable. Switching trough the posts and trying to find the next part of the chain isn’t optimal. For example we’re currently in the 2204th character and imagine reading that from a 250 character limited thread …</p>

<p>These were the 2 main reasons why personal blogs should make a comeback. Creating a blog is a really easy task and if you have cool stories to tell us, why not <a href="https://startafuckingblog.com">start your own blog</a> in 2023?</p>

<h2 id="thank-you">Thank You!</h2>

<p>Batuhan Yılmaz - 26.01.2023 - 4/100</p>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>bthyilmaz@outlook.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey guys I’m Batuhan and todays blogpost I’m going to talk about why personal blogging should make a comeback. Actually I had been considering to write a blogpost on that topic for some time. When I came across with The Verge’s this post about bringing the blogging back and its importance for the internet. I decided to write my troughs on that.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Finally HTTPS!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/finally-https/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Finally HTTPS!" /><published>2023-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/finally-https</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/finally-https/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone, I’m Batuhan and today I’m going to talk about how did I got the HTTPS working with my web server over cloudflare tunnel. Before starting that tutorial I should say that what works for me may not work for you, so please think before following these steps, in any case you can always come to our <a href="https://discord.gg/5p27ZdzQzF">discord server</a> from the About page and get more help from there. So without any further words lets go.</p>

<h2 id="why-im-creating-this-blogpost-its-just-too-easy">Why I’m creating this blogpost it’s just too easy.</h2>

<ul>
  <li>I can hear you saying that becouse it’s really easy to create a certificate and use with your domain when it comes to the Cloudflare and Cloudflare Tunnel. When you enable it from the Cloudflare dashboard, it encrypts everything for you, and it just works generally. But when it comes to hosting my web archive using Apache 2 with zero extra configuration, things become a bit problematic with resulting in mixed content and a website that doesn’t work.</li>
</ul>

<p><img src="https://archive.thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/Media/Images/blog/Screenshot%202022-04-02%20at%2010.53.34.png" alt="Mixed content error" /></p>

<ul>
  <li>The error that you’re currently seeing above this text was the main reason why I didn’t had HTTPS until now. At the beginning I was tried everything at the Cloudflare side to fix it but nothing has worked until I realised that main problem was at the server side. As I said at the beginning of the post, the server side was just a zero configration apache2 installation and was using the http protocol. And this was a problem for the Cloudflare and the browsers becouse while the main content is being served as https other stuff as well as the files and medias was still on the http and this was the problem.</li>
  <li>The fix was actually too simple and after fixing it just inside 3 minutes I just kept thinking “Why the fuck I wasn’t knew that before!?”.  But yeah I fixed it in the end :).</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="how-did-i-fix-it">How did I fix it?</h2>

<ul>
  <li>So let’s come to the part where contains the fix. It’s very simple and as I said before it only takes like 3 minutes to fix it. So here is the step by step guide:</li>
</ul>

<p>Step 1 - Update the apache2 and OpenSSL into latest version avabile:</p>

<ol>
  <li>First you have to make sure that you have the latest version of the Apache2 and OpenSSL installed on your server just in case and for that just use the commands below to update them to latest version.
    <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>sudo apt update
sudo apt install apache2 openssl
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>Step 2 - Generate your certificates from Cloudflare Dashboard</p>

<ol>
  <li>Now go to your Cloudflare Dashboard and login. After that select your domain and go to the SSL/TLS section from the sidebar.
<img src="https://archive.thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/Media/Images/blog/Screenshot%202022-12-02%20at%2022.58.50.png" alt="" />
 In this page select the Full encryption for the best result.</li>
  <li>After enabling the encryption go to the origin server section from the sidebar and create a certificate for your server. This certificate is gonna be used for the HTTPS and vertification of our server by the Cloudflare Tunnel.</li>
</ol>

<p><img src="https://archive.thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/Media/Images/blog/Screenshot%202022-12-02%20at%2023.04.33.png" alt="" /></p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>To create your certificate  press on the Create Certificate button and follow the pages.

![](https://archive.thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/Media/Images/blog/Screenshot%202022-12-02%20at%2023.04.48.png)
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Press to the create button at the bottom and you should be able to see the page below.</p>

<p><img src="https://archive.thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/Media/Images/blog/Screenshot%202022-12-02%20at%2023.06.08.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Now Cloudflare gives us 2 very random looking text outputs over there, the top one is your public certificate and the bottom one is your private key. Please make sure you saved them locally to your computer before pressing to the blue button, becouse as the name suggests the private key is private and Cloudflare doesn’t stores it for you and you won’t be able to see it again. And you have to save it to somewhere you know becouse it’s needed for HTTPS.
Now after creating your certificate and saving it on somewhere safe on your computer, it’s time to log into our server and configure the apache2.</p>

<p><img src="https://archive.thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/Media/Images/blog/Screenshot%202023-01-04%20at%2012.25.18.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Now change your dir into <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">/etc/apache2</code>and create a folder named Certificates with the command below</p>
<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>cd /etc/apache2 &amp;&amp; mkdir certificates
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>After that place the certificates that you’ve saved your computer to that folder. The important thing is do not save the public and private key into same file! I suggest you to save the public key as <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">domain.key.pub</code> and the private key as <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">domain.key</code>.  This will make managing your certificates for the different websites if you’re hosting multiple sites on the same machine like me.</p>

<p><img src="https://archive.thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/Media/Images/blog/Screenshot%202023-01-23%20at%2022.33.27.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>And now, the only thing has left is to add these certs to our  websites and it’s actually very easy.
First you have to enable the ssl plugin of the apache and than add these certs to our website’s config file. 
To enable the Apache2’s ssl and rewrite plugin use the command I put down below.</p>
<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>sudo a2enmod ssl &amp;&amp; sudo a2enmod rewrite
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>after running that command go to your websites config and add these 3 lines to your config.</p>
<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>SSLEngine on
SSLCertificateFile /etc/apache2/certs/&lt;your-cert.crt&gt;
SSLCertificateKeyFile /etc/apache2/certs/&lt;your-key.key&gt;
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>Make sure that these lines are placed under the VirtualHost tag, otherwise Apache won’t gonna use our certs and we’ll end with the same situation which we don’t want. So after that it’s done. Now restart the Apache and you’re ready to go!</p>

<p>This is how I get my https working on my server with Cloudflare Tunnel and apache2 I hope this post helps to you in any case you can always come to our <a href="https://discord.gg/5p27ZdzQzF">discord server</a> and get more help from there.</p>

<h2 id="thank-you">Thank You!</h2>

<p>Batuhan Yılmaz - 23.01.2023 - 3/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>bthyilmaz@outlook.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello everyone, I’m Batuhan and today I’m going to talk about how did I got the HTTPS working with my web server over cloudflare tunnel. Before starting that tutorial I should say that what works for me may not work for you, so please think before following these steps, in any case you can always come to our discord server from the About page and get more help from there. So without any further words lets go.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Beginning of the #100DaysToOffload</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/beginning-of-the-100daystooffload/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Beginning of the #100DaysToOffload" /><published>2023-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/beginning-of-the-100daystooffload</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/beginning-of-the-100daystooffload/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone, I’m Batuhan and today I’m going to challenge myself to write 100 blogposts in 2023 and this is the second post of this challenge! If you’re wondering what is the first one of this challenge is, it’s the post before that post. [(Very very good Engrish momentum :D) Since I’m typing these posts without using any translators or tools like QuillBot or Grammarly to fix my typos and using my own brain to create these sentences. We all could expect some errors because I’m still a newcomer English.]</p>

<p>So anyway, what is the #100DaysToOffload at the first place. Well a simple explanation of this challenge is writing 100 blogposts on your own personal blog inside 365 days. These blogposts doesn’t has to be so long or so short or doesn’t have to stick into a topic. You can write whatever you want into your personal blogsite and have fun with it. It’s a very simple challenge and this is why I’m going to try myself out on writing 100 blogposts until the 2024 comes.</p>

<p>You can go and check out the <a href="https://100daystooffload.com">#100DaysToOffload</a> website to get more information about the challenge and some people who sucsessfuly completed that challenge. Hopefully at the end of the year I’ll be at that list too. Who knows.  We all gonna see that at the end of this year hopefully.</p>

<p><img src="https://archive.thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/Media/Wallpapers/wallpaper-repository/Wallpapers/fog.png" alt="Experimental emedded image" /></p>
<h2 id="thank-you">Thank You!</h2>

<p>Batuhan Yılmaz - 22.01.2023 - 2/100</p>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>bthyilmaz@outlook.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello everyone, I’m Batuhan and today I’m going to challenge myself to write 100 blogposts in 2023 and this is the second post of this challenge! If you’re wondering what is the first one of this challenge is, it’s the post before that post. [(Very very good Engrish momentum :D) Since I’m typing these posts without using any translators or tools like QuillBot or Grammarly to fix my typos and using my own brain to create these sentences. We all could expect some errors because I’m still a newcomer English.]]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Using an iPhone 6 Plus as a secondary phone in 2023</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/using-an-iphone-6-plus-as-a-secondary-phone-in-2023/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using an iPhone 6 Plus as a secondary phone in 2023" /><published>2023-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/using-an-iphone-6-plus-as-a-secondary-phone-in-2023</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/using-an-iphone-6-plus-as-a-secondary-phone-in-2023/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone, I’m Batuhan and this blogpost has written from my new iPhone 6 Plus! I’ve got this phone from my cousin and it’s been used ver carefully and it runs pretty great. And for that I wanted see how it holds up trough a day and for that I carried it with me to the school and it made trough the day without any big problems. Only problem that I had with this phone is it has a defective battery in it and it doesn’t lasts long. Like since the beginning of the test, I had to plug it in for 3 times and charge it up up to 80 percent in order to keep that thing up. Otherwise it works perfectly fine for almost any tasks. Like writing this blogpost on the Evernote app, taking some photos using the camera or listening music trough the Apple Music. 
<img src="https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/789025765055791104/1066087440877637703/IMG_0010.PNG" alt="iPhone's battery health" />
Like as you can see on the screenshot that I put there the battery life isn’t good and it could shut itself down even on %60 but I think this is also because that phone was in it’s box since the summer of 2020 and batter could be degraded because of that and I think it’ll fix itself after some charge cycles. Also becouse of these shutdowns the phone put itself into a mode named “Peak performace” and becouse of that it runs slower than it should. But it’s an easy fix. Just replace the battery and it’s back on the roads with full performance. But for now I’m not planning to do it</p>

<p>Another problem this phone has is it’s 16 GB of storage. This phone only has 16 GBs of storage space and 4 GB of it is already filled up by the iOS 12. Which leaves me only 12 GBs of usable storage and after installing like 7 app that I use daily it fills the half of it’s usable storage. If you’re the one who only uses his phone for phone calls and never installs any other apps than Whatsapp, than there is plenty of empty storage for you. But not for me.
<img src="https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/789025765055791104/1066086733931876372/IMG_0012.PNG" alt="iPhone Storage usage" />
As you can see over there I already filled the half if it’s storage space and there is only my music and some apps and it’s half full already I don’t even have the quarter of the things that I have on my 128 GB iPhone 7 Plus. Which I already filled up the 40 GB of this space lol.
<img src="https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/789025765055791104/1066087802606989403/IMG_0014.PNG" alt="HomeScreen of the iPhone 6 Plus" />
As you can see there is only 8 apps and 98 music not a single photo on my gallery (expect the iCloud photos which aren’t saved locally on my phone). This is the only problem that I haven’t with this phone as I said. Otherwise this phone is a very nice phone and still usable after all these years. It’a still fast and well supported when age of this phone is considered. And I do believe that this phone would became a better phone with some jailbreaking and a battery swap. In future I’ll try to make this phone a better phone but for now I don’t have the enough time and money to do the things I planned.</p>

<p>So this was a simple blogpost that I wrote after using it as my second phone for a day. I’m planning to only use this phone as my daily driver and make a longer and detailed blogpost about how it’s usable and using it with some jailbreak tweaks. Also I’m gonna write a blogpost about my 7 Plus too but for now I don’t have much free time to sit on my computer and write blogposts. So sorry for that.  But I’m generally updating my <a href="https://fosstodon.org/@B4tuhanY1lmaz">Fosstodon account</a>. You can always come and follow me over there. Also don’t forget to join our Discord server if you’re looking for somewhere to hang up.</p>

<h1 id="thank-you">Thank You!</h1>

<p>Batuhan Yılmaz - 20.01.2023</p>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>bthyilmaz@outlook.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello everyone, I’m Batuhan and this blogpost has written from my new iPhone 6 Plus! I’ve got this phone from my cousin and it’s been used ver carefully and it runs pretty great. And for that I wanted see how it holds up trough a day and for that I carried it with me to the school and it made trough the day without any big problems. Only problem that I had with this phone is it has a defective battery in it and it doesn’t lasts long. Like since the beginning of the test, I had to plug it in for 3 times and charge it up up to 80 percent in order to keep that thing up. Otherwise it works perfectly fine for almost any tasks. Like writing this blogpost on the Evernote app, taking some photos using the camera or listening music trough the Apple Music. Like as you can see on the screenshot that I put there the battery life isn’t good and it could shut itself down even on %60 but I think this is also because that phone was in it’s box since the summer of 2020 and batter could be degraded because of that and I think it’ll fix itself after some charge cycles. Also becouse of these shutdowns the phone put itself into a mode named “Peak performace” and becouse of that it runs slower than it should. But it’s an easy fix. Just replace the battery and it’s back on the roads with full performance. But for now I’m not planning to do it]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Here comes 2023. What do I expect?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/here-comes-the-2023-what-do-i-expect/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Here comes 2023. What do I expect?" /><published>2022-12-31T01:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-12-31T01:30:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/here-comes-the-2023-what-do-i-expect</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/here-comes-the-2023-what-do-i-expect/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone, I’m Batuhan Yılmaz and as we all know another year has come to it’s end. With it’s good sides and bad sides it was a good year for me, becouse recovering from the global pandemic and turning back to schools and the social life after 2 years of lockdown was a huge plus for me.  With it’s good sides and bad sides it was a good year.</p>

<h2 id="what-do-i-expect-from-the-2023">What do I expect from the 2023?</h2>

<p>So yeah a complete new year and of course things will change a bit, but I’m not into that “A new year a new me” shit becouse we all know that most of us doesn’t gets their new year plans done. 
So all I expect from the 2023 is just succsess on the final year of the highschool. Becouse in June 2023, I’ll take an exam to attend my dream college and become a college-graduated software engineer. We all know that everyone looking for a Carbon Developer that has 10 years of experience and gradue from Harvard. And becouse of that I have to work hard and get into that college.  Other than that I just expect another good year like 2022.</p>

<h2 id="acknowledge-of-2022">Acknowledge of 2022</h2>

<p>As my last words of 2022, I want to say thanks to everyone who made 2022 an awesome year for me. I really can’t imagine how 2022 would’ve been without them. I’m not just talking about the people I talk to in my life. I’m also talking about the people on my Discord server. You guys are just awesome in every way, and I want to thank you for making the last two years of my life  awesome! I wish you all have the best in 2023.</p>

<h2 id="one-more-thing">One more thing</h2>

<p>As one more thing, I asked ChatGPT to write a blogpost about new year and here’s the result:</p>

<p><img src="https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/789025765055791104/1058767628962893874/chrome_SB5SsnTrZP.png" alt="ChatGPT Answer" /></p>
<h2 id="thank-you">Thank You.</h2>
<p>Batuhan Yılmaz - 31.12.22</p>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>bthyilmaz@outlook.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello everyone, I’m Batuhan Yılmaz and as we all know another year has come to it’s end. With it’s good sides and bad sides it was a good year for me, becouse recovering from the global pandemic and turning back to schools and the social life after 2 years of lockdown was a huge plus for me. With it’s good sides and bad sides it was a good year.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Here goes the November 2022</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/here-goes-the-november-2022/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Here goes the November 2022" /><published>2022-11-30T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-11-30T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/here-goes-the-november-2022</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/here-goes-the-november-2022/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone I’m Batuhan Yılmaz.
It’s been long time since last time I publish something to my blog. 5 months since my last post and some stuff has been changed since then.  Like the way I host this blog, the look and feel, the city I’m in and etc. I’m not gonna talk about them for now becouse they’re topic for anpther blogpost. The reason why I didn’t published anything is actually becouse I don’t have mcuh free time for writing up.  I become a 12th grade student in Turkey and the achievements I’ll get this year is so important for the university that I’ll go. And as we all know a good university means a good carrier and if I want to be a Software engineer with a good salary then I have to work hard this year. Anyway back to topic. The reason for this blogpost was just to inform the 1 person who reads my post that I’m maintaining this website.🙂</p>

<h2 id="one-more-thing">One more thing</h2>

<ul>
  <li>I know this header may sound exiting but actually it’s not really much. As you guys know, I do selfhost this webpage and my server don’t gets the best uptimes and for that I decided to use the <a href="https://codeberg.page">Codeberg Pages</a> as a backup site under the blog subdomain and use the main domain for the main site. Hopefully it will be a better solution as a backup.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="thank-you">Thank You.</h2>

<ul>
  <li>Batuhan Yılmaz - 30.11.22</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>bthyilmaz@outlook.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello everyone I’m Batuhan Yılmaz. It’s been long time since last time I publish something to my blog. 5 months since my last post and some stuff has been changed since then. Like the way I host this blog, the look and feel, the city I’m in and etc. I’m not gonna talk about them for now becouse they’re topic for anpther blogpost. The reason why I didn’t published anything is actually becouse I don’t have mcuh free time for writing up. I become a 12th grade student in Turkey and the achievements I’ll get this year is so important for the university that I’ll go. And as we all know a good university means a good carrier and if I want to be a Software engineer with a good salary then I have to work hard this year. Anyway back to topic. The reason for this blogpost was just to inform the 1 person who reads my post that I’m maintaining this website.🙂]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I’m using an Hackintosh for 6 months. Now what?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/im-using-an-hackintosh-for-6-months-now-what/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I’m using an Hackintosh for 6 months. Now what?" /><published>2022-06-23T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-06-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/im-using-an-hackintosh-for-6-months-now-what</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/im-using-an-hackintosh-for-6-months-now-what/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone I’m Batuhan and I’m a Linux user for the past 8 years and I’m using an hackintosh as my daily driver on desktop for 6 months. And I’m always asking myself that question: Now what? Am I gonna ditch the Linux on desktop or just gonna reinstall Fedora? Let’s talk about that.</p>

<h2 id="beginning">Beginning</h2>
<p>So the idea of hackintoshing my Dell Optiplex 7050 was a thing that I really wanted to do since the 2019, the year that I got my computer. Since then I tried hackintoshing 3 times until I got it running sucsessfully on the hardware. Before that I was using an Ivy Bridge computer with macOS High Sierra running on it with clover bootloader. And since I was knew a bit about clover and I wanted to use clover for my second hackintosh and it was unsuccessful. For some reason the OS just kept kernel panicking and I was gave up on it. Than 1 year later I found out that a bootloader named OpenCore exist and I wanted to try it for a second time. And the result of it was better. I was able to get the installation screen and I was able to install macOS Catalina into the HDD and it was working fine. Until I realized that the GPU acceleration wasn’t working on either iGPU or dGPU. So in there I was gaved up second time. And after doing some research I found out that a guy got macOS running perfectly fine on his Dell Optiplex 7050 Micro which doesn’t have much difference than the tower which I have. So I started to working on his EFI and after tweaking it a bit I was able to fix the GPU problem that I had and was able to run Catalina perfectly fine. Than I tried upgrading the OS like a real mac and it ran pretty well. I was able to upgrade to the Monterey from Cataling and I didn’t had to change anything on the EFI side. I was too happy about that becouse not just I got it working without any problem, I was got an Unix based OS which could run some of the Linux apps that I was using a lot via the Macports and can run the properitary Adobe programs that I need soo much becouse of our video projects.</p>

<h2 id="what-im-gonna-do-in-future">What I’m gonna do in future?</h2>
<p>So as you know the next release of the macOS named Ventura got announced and cut support for lot’s of devices. So the good side is it’s compatible with my hardware and the SMBIOS I do use so I can upgrade it. But I’m not gonna upgrade to the Ventura anytime soon. Even if it becomes stable. The reason for this is becouse there is not a real difference between these 2 versions of the OS. And there is always the risk of breaking a working system which I don’t really want to do. But when the patchers for the old hardware comes out I’ll try to get it running on my old computer which has a Intel Core I5-3570K CPU in it.</p>

<h2 id="what-im-doing-with-my-hackintosh">What I’m doing with my Hackintosh?</h2>
<p>So let’s come to the question that’s important for me. What I’m doing with my computer. So the main thing is I do play games like OSU!, Minecraft, CIV6 and Terraria ,doing video editing a lot. Like I do have 3 different video editing software installed on my computer and I do use 2 of them a lot. These are the KDEnlive and Adobe Premiere PRO. Since I know both of these software I do use them. KDEnlive for basic video editing like cutting videos, merging videos or just adding a background music to them. And using Adobe Premiere PRO for advenced tasks. And virtualizing stuff with the UTM APP and QEMU. Otherwise I’m mostly using it for web browsing and my computer really does these tasks really well.</p>

<p>Also I want to point a thing that most people online just loves to judge these Dell Optiplex users and says “Oh do you have a Optiplex man my toaster is more powerfull than your computer”. I know most people not gonna think same with me but I believe that these computers are really fast and powerful computers if you use them in the right configration. Like using custom AMD GPU drivers named NimeZ on Windows 10 really unlocks the potential of the stock GPU that computer comes with.</p>

<h2 id="now-what">Now what?</h2>
<p>So as I asked on the header of that post is “Now what?” So I’ll keep it using until I decide to switch back to Linux on my desktop. But until that I’m going to keep it on the macOS Monterey and use it for my daily bases and if I do need a Linux environment runs on bare metal hardware, I can just use my server for that. It has the complete same hardware in it expect the storage side and I even used it while building the EFI and it helped me a lot while tinkering stuff.  So even if I need Linux I don’t need to install it.</p>

<h2 id="should-you-create-a-hackintosh">Should you create a hackintosh?</h2>
<p>So if you gonna ask me that question my answer will be no, unless you have free time and want to mess up with your hardware. But why I said no? Becouse believe or not building an hackintosh needs a lot of time and passion. It doesn’t ends with just installing the OS, you need to do lot’s of testing after installing OS, like getting the sleep working, mapping your USB ports, getting wifi and bluetooth working and etc. It needs lot’s of time and tinkering to get it running stable as a real mac.  You don’t have to do these stuff or have to tinker that much on even installing Gentoo, I’m serious about that. If you need a computer for production I just suggest you to go and install either Windows or Linux. But even ef you want to do an hackintosh than good luck man, just make sure you have an extra computer while working on your hackintosh.</p>

<p>Thanks for reading that blog post. This was a post that I really wanted to share with you for long time. If you want to build a hackintosh or discuss about technology, please join our <a href="https://discord.gg/jt5wXUKa">Discord server</a> !</p>

<h1 id="thank-you">Thank You!</h1>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>bthyilmaz@outlook.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello everyone I’m Batuhan and I’m a Linux user for the past 8 years and I’m using an hackintosh as my daily driver on desktop for 6 months. And I’m always asking myself that question: Now what? Am I gonna ditch the Linux on desktop or just gonna reinstall Fedora? Let’s talk about that.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Configuring Jekyll</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/configuring-jekyll/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Configuring Jekyll" /><published>2022-06-16T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-06-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/configuring-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/configuring-jekyll/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone I’m Batuhan and today I’m going to talk about how I configured my Jekyll Blog from it’s stock look and feel to the current look and feel.</p>

<h2 id="installing-jekyll-and-its-plugins">Installing Jekyll and it’s plugins</h2>
<p>Firstly you need to install Jekyll according to the documention. <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/docs/installation/ubuntu/">Jekyll on Ubuntu | Jekyll • Simple, blog-aware, static sites</a> Since I’m using Ubuntu Server I linked the one for Ubuntu but it could work on other Debian based distros. Than I installed the<a href="https://github.com/tocttou/hacker-blog">GitHub - tocttou/hacker-blog</a> theme by cloning it into a folder and configuring the _config.yml file.</p>
<h3 id="plugins">Plugins</h3>
<p>Of course I’m using couple of plugins to improve the Jekyll experience.
These are the</p>
<ul>
  <li>Jekyll SEO tag</li>
  <li>Jekyll Admin</li>
  <li>Jekyll Sitemap</li>
  <li>Jekyll Paginate
I’m using these plugins for improving the blog and creating posts easier. The Admin plugin is generally disabled because of the security flaws that it has but when creating posts I’m enabling it, creating post and disabling it.</li>
</ul>

<p>This was basically an easy thing to setup as I want. Now let’s talk about why I’m not hosting that website on a GitHub pages and using my own server.
So basically hosting stuff on my own server is always better than hosting it somewhere online. But I’m gonna host a backup on Github pages too. Because my server could be unreliable sometimes and having a backup on Github is always a nice thing.</p>

<h2 id="how-i-setup-the-server-side">How I setup the server side</h2>
<p>So lets come to the most important part. Most people online has setup their server using ngix web server but I already have a Apache2 server setup and I don’t want to mess up with my server by setting up another web server or trying to get Apache working while breaking other websites. So for that I just used the Jekyll’s built in server function and systemd. 
But in there I had to install every GEM that I installed on my user on the root user to get the systemd serivce working. Otherwise it would show as working but in journals Ruby just spams a lot of can’t find gem errors. But it works now and here is the system.service file that I used for my setup:</p>
<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>[Unit]
Description=Jekyll
After=cloudflared.service # Staring it after cloudflared. You can change that.
[Service]
User=&lt;user&gt; # You need to replace it with the user that you want to run your blog.
TimeoutStartSec=0
Type=notify
WorkingDirectory=&lt;directory of your blog&gt;
ExecStart=/home/&lt;user&gt;/gems/bin/jekyll serve #The Jekyll executable that's located in your users home folder. You have to change that tho.
Restart=on-failure
RestartSec=10s

[Install]
WantedBy=multi-user.target
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>It was that simple and hopefully it works for you too. But always there is a chance of a thing that works for me not works for you. So in that situation you can come to our <a href="https://discord.gg/jt5wXUKa">Discord server</a> and get help from there.</p>

<h3 id="thank-you">Thank You.</h3>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>bthyilmaz@outlook.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello everyone I’m Batuhan and today I’m going to talk about how I configured my Jekyll Blog from it’s stock look and feel to the current look and feel.]]></summary></entry></feed>