<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" /><updated>2023-05-09T16:41:26+01:00</updated><id>http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Batuhan’s Blog</title><subtitle>The Batuhan's Blog</subtitle><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>batuhan@thebatuhansnetwork.xyz</email></author><entry><title type="html">It Was Firewall</title><link href="http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/it-was-firewall/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="It Was Firewall" /><published>2023-05-09T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-05-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/it-was-firewall</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/it-was-firewall/"><![CDATA[<p>Last night I did some security hardening on my server and noticed that after rebooting it all my remote connections went down.</p>

<p>Syncthing over port 9000, XRDP over port 3386 and uptime kuma over port 8000 was stopped working and even tho I added them to UFW it shouldn’t be the problem right? Wrong! For some reason UFW was still blocking every single connection other than port 22 and 9090 and my only fix for it was disabling UFW.</p>

<p>Disabling it fixed my problems instantly and I was happy becouse I was able to get my stuff up and running. But the problem now I don’t have any firewalls securing my server. And I think I’ll go that way but it isn’t secure. But even tho this isn’t a secure way to do that, this server doesn’t actually open to world wide web other than tailscale network and my blog is being hosted using Cloudflare Tunnel and it doesn’t directly opens my port 80 to open web.</p>

<p>So I think it’s safe to say that I’m still secure with my setup and since I don’t have any directly open ports. It isn’t possible to have an attack on my server unless some malicious device pops up on tailscale.</p>

<h2 id="reply-via-e-mail">Reply via <a href="mailto://batuhan@thebatuhansnetwork.xyz">E-Mail</a></h2>
<h2 id="thank-you">Thank You!</h2>
<p>Batuhan Yılmaz - 09.05.2023 - 17/100</p>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>batuhan@thebatuhansnetwork.xyz</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last night I did some security hardening on my server and noticed that after rebooting it all my remote connections went down.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recreating Optiplex Server</title><link href="http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/recreating-optiplex-server/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recreating Optiplex Server" /><published>2023-05-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-05-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/recreating-optiplex-server</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/recreating-optiplex-server/"><![CDATA[<p>2 weeks ago I got myself 2 used Optiplexes and my idea with them was recreating my old setup and today I’m going to recreate my Optiplex Server. Before creating it I planned my use cases.</p>
<ol>
  <li>A webserver inside a Debian VM</li>
  <li>A Nextcloud server inside Ubuntu Server 22.04 VM</li>
  <li>SMB server for file sharing on local</li>
  <li>A Minecraft server running bare metal</li>
  <li>And some tiny services like dashy and uptime kuma inside a Arch VM. (I use arch btw)
These were the summary of things I planned to run on this server. So for that I needed to find the perfect OS for it. What I mean by that is, it should be optimized for virtualisation and it should be stable. And for these reasons I decided to go with Rocky Linux 9.1. I went their website, downloaded iso, burned using balenaEtcher and step 1 was completed. !<img src="https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/789025765055791104/1105173951015035091/DBBB546C-E464-4A43-95F2-9B06204311BA.png" alt="etcher" /></li>
</ol>

<p>Step 2 was finding an suitable OS drive. 
At the beginning I considered using a USB3.0 32GB USB stick but than I saw that these usb sticks were good at storing files but not at randomly accsesing them. I tried installing Debian onto this 32GB Kioxia USB 3.0 stick and it ran slow as hell. And becouse of that I decided to go with an SSD and I brought out a 240GB Crucial BX500 for that !<img src="https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/789025765055791104/1105173950578835566/A959E34E-8708-4BBC-ACF6-8079C1D5F5CB.jpeg" alt="SSD and Optiplex server" />
I preferred this SSD becouse it was my best option for it’s price. Thing makes this SSD better is it’s dram. Dram is important for random acsessing the data on drive and since I’m gonna run bunch of different virtual machines on it at the same time, it’s a feature that I need. Also when compared to it’s dramless same priced alternatives like WD Green. 
After installing Rocky Linux 9 I greeted with the beautiful Gnome 40 desktop and it was ready to go. All things I needed (QEMU, Virt-Manager, Cockpit, HTTPD, OpenSSL, Samba) was installed upon installation since I selected them and only thing I needed to do was condfiguring them.</p>

<h2 id="configration">Configration</h2>
<p>My another reason for going with Rocky Linux was using terminal minimal as possible. Becouse since this OS is designed to be fast, production ready and easy to use I wanted to done most of the configration like users and samba shares over at Cockpit webui and for that I installed the cockpit-shares and cockpit-identification plugins and I’ve done configuring Samba without entering a single command. But of course when it comes to other parts such as setting up the Debian VM and other stuff I needed command line and here comes it.</p>

<h3 id="debian-vm">Debian VM</h3>
<blockquote>
  <p>A webserver inside a Debian VM 
<img src="https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/789025765055791104/1105173951476416616/Screenshot_2023-05-07_at_22.34.03.png" alt="CockpitUI" />
As you can see on top I’ve created a tiny VM and it’s been serving as my webserver since the day I posted <a href="https://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/the-page-you-currently-in/">this post</a> and you’re proably reading this from that virtual machine too.
<img src="https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/789025765055791104/1105173951749038230/Screenshot_2023-05-07_at_22.35.18.png" alt="Htop" /></p>
</blockquote>

<p>As you can see only 84MB of ram usage! While setting this VM up I’ve gone with less things installed as possible and when the setup has finished I had a very simple OS with base system and nothing more. Than I installed some stuff I needed for Jekyll ,apache2 and openssh-server becouse ssh doesn’t uses too much memory and it’s just easier for me to ssh in instead of opening a VNC client and connecting to VM. Since it doesn’t has a GUI. 
You may ask if this VM is that simple, what brings this website to me? Well answer is simple. It’s CloudFlare tunnel. I’ve installed it into servers itself and than created a Virtual network for this VM so it’s reachable from server and than I used it’s virtual IP and it worked! 
With that Crucial SSD booting this VM only takes a seconds and feels same as running a container.</p>

<h3 id="ubuntu-server">Ubuntu Server</h3>
<blockquote>
  <p>A Nextcloud server inside Ubuntu Server 22.04 VM</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Configuring Ubuntu Server VM was very simple. I just used the Nextcloud Snap package for it and with sime tiny configrations it was done. I’m not actually a fan of snaps becouse they’re bloaed as hell and runs much slower when compared to it’s alternative Faltpaks but since this VMs only purpose is Nextcloud I’m completely fine with it. 
I gaved the same amount of resources expect sotrage and usage on this VM is way more than other one like 400Mb while idling but this was expected and even under load it doesn’t goes higher than 800Mbs and I’m happy with it.</p>

<h3 id="extras">Extras</h3>
<p>And I’ve installed some extras like Resillio Sync for file synchronising, Xrdp for be able to login to GUI remotely and autoSSH for port forwarding to a VPS.</p>

<p>In a summary this was it guys. Of course things went more complicated and I tried to keep it simple. I’m planning to host myself a <a href="https://sr.ht/~tsileo/microblog.pub/">microblog.pub</a> instance like <a href="https://qrk.social/">Kev Quirk</a> and a <a href="https://sr.ht/~thecashewtrader/minv/">minv</a>
server but for now I don’t have enough time to do these but when I do I’m gonna keep you guys updated about it. If you have any questions or need support for your server you can come and check out our <a href="https://discord.gg/5p27ZdzQzF">Discord server</a> .</p>

<h2 id="reply-via-e-mail">Reply via <a href="mailto://batuhan@thebatuhansnetwork.xyz">e-mail</a></h2>
<h2 id="thank-you">Thank You!</h2>
<p>Batuhan Yılmaz - 08.05.2023 - 16/100</p>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>batuhan@thebatuhansnetwork.xyz</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[2 weeks ago I got myself 2 used Optiplexes and my idea with them was recreating my old setup and today I’m going to recreate my Optiplex Server. Before creating it I planned my use cases. A webserver inside a Debian VM A Nextcloud server inside Ubuntu Server 22.04 VM SMB server for file sharing on local A Minecraft server running bare metal And some tiny services like dashy and uptime kuma inside a Arch VM. (I use arch btw) These were the summary of things I planned to run on this server. So for that I needed to find the perfect OS for it. What I mean by that is, it should be optimized for virtualisation and it should be stable. And for these reasons I decided to go with Rocky Linux 9.1. I went their website, downloaded iso, burned using balenaEtcher and step 1 was completed. !]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Today is 6 May 2023</title><link href="http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/today-is-6-may-2023/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Today is 6 May 2023" /><published>2023-05-05T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-05-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/today-is-6-may-2023</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/today-is-6-may-2023/"><![CDATA[<p>Dear diary. Today is 06 May 2023. Today is birthday of my girl bestfriend and I hope she’s having a great day but other than that. 3 months has passed since the earthquake happened. If you ask us. We’re doing completely well on that. We recreated our life in past 3 months and succeeded. We’re now in a safe and secure place. Everything is going great on it’s place. But the problem is they forgot it. Everyone expect people who affected by earthquake has already forgot what happened and everybody is focused on election. Just 2 month ago the earthquake was at the main focus of the politicans but now nobody talks about it. I watched the place I called as home collapsing. I watched the place I called home to became a graveyard for more than 50k people just in seconds. I watched people to cry out becouse of their loved ones. Not the things or houses but people they called as home, people they called as family … and much more. They’re gone and no one is able to revive them. So what now? Are we gonna just forget them, are we gonna forget how they left people on their own, are we gonna forget survivors? Are we gonna forget people who is responsible for that? Are we gonna forget people who left us to death? Are we just gonna forget everything? Looks like we have to becouse everyone has forgot it and is there any reason to keep these memories alive?
Turkish people loves to forget and this time it didn’t take long for that to happen. But man a disaster like that … Last week I went to Malatya to see how people doing over there and seems like life on Malatya began to turn back to normal and everything going on it’s way but there is a one big problem. The landscape of this city we used to see isn’t there anymore. Without all these buildings and people who makes this city different isn’t there anymore and without them this place feels so strange to me. I used to call this place as home with everything and everyone inside but now. I’m a complete stranger to this place and I won’t be able to be part of Malatya anymore.</p>

<p>I hope this earthquake changes something over at people becouse I don’t want that to happen again and I don’t want to loose my home one more time.</p>

<h2 id="thank-you">Thank You!</h2>
<p>Batuhan Yılmaz - 06.05.2023 - 15/100</p>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>batuhan@thebatuhansnetwork.xyz</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dear diary. Today is 06 May 2023. Today is birthday of my girl bestfriend and I hope she’s having a great day but other than that. 3 months has passed since the earthquake happened. If you ask us. We’re doing completely well on that. We recreated our life in past 3 months and succeeded. We’re now in a safe and secure place. Everything is going great on it’s place. But the problem is they forgot it. Everyone expect people who affected by earthquake has already forgot what happened and everybody is focused on election. Just 2 month ago the earthquake was at the main focus of the politicans but now nobody talks about it. I watched the place I called as home collapsing. I watched the place I called home to became a graveyard for more than 50k people just in seconds. I watched people to cry out becouse of their loved ones. Not the things or houses but people they called as home, people they called as family … and much more. They’re gone and no one is able to revive them. So what now? Are we gonna just forget them, are we gonna forget how they left people on their own, are we gonna forget survivors? Are we gonna forget people who is responsible for that? Are we gonna forget people who left us to death? Are we just gonna forget everything? Looks like we have to becouse everyone has forgot it and is there any reason to keep these memories alive? Turkish people loves to forget and this time it didn’t take long for that to happen. But man a disaster like that … Last week I went to Malatya to see how people doing over there and seems like life on Malatya began to turn back to normal and everything going on it’s way but there is a one big problem. The landscape of this city we used to see isn’t there anymore. Without all these buildings and people who makes this city different isn’t there anymore and without them this place feels so strange to me. I used to call this place as home with everything and everyone inside but now. I’m a complete stranger to this place and I won’t be able to be part of Malatya anymore.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The page you’re currently in being hosted from a VM</title><link href="http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/the-page-you-currently-in/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The page you’re currently in being hosted from a VM" /><published>2023-05-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-05-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/the-page-you-currently-in</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/the-page-you-currently-in/"><![CDATA[<p>So today I got my new server and I’m gonna post it tomorrow and the page you’re currently in is being hosted from a tiny and minimal as hell Debian 11 virtual machine with only 16GB of storage and 1GB of ram. My plan for memory was actually only 512Mb but for some reasons setting up Jekyll needed compiling some packages and 512 wasn’t enough for them to compile. They just spammed me out segmentation and unkown instruction errors and when I saw the resource usage I saw memory was filled up and ot just memory, even the swap space was filled up. But in the end I got it up and running.</p>

<p>This was just a micro post about it and right now I’m writing up the actual post.</p>

<h2 id="thank-you">Thank You!</h2>
<p>Batuhan Yılmaz - 05.05.2023 - 14/100</p>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>batuhan@thebatuhansnetwork.xyz</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So today I got my new server and I’m gonna post it tomorrow and the page you’re currently in is being hosted from a tiny and minimal as hell Debian 11 virtual machine with only 16GB of storage and 1GB of ram. My plan for memory was actually only 512Mb but for some reasons setting up Jekyll needed compiling some packages and 512 wasn’t enough for them to compile. They just spammed me out segmentation and unkown instruction errors and when I saw the resource usage I saw memory was filled up and ot just memory, even the swap space was filled up. But in the end I got it up and running.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">iPhone 7 Plus review. Is it still usable in 2023?</title><link href="http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/iphone-7-plus-review-is-it-still-usable-in-2023/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="iPhone 7 Plus review. Is it still usable in 2023?" /><published>2023-04-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-04-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/iphone-7-plus-review-is-it-still-usable-in-2023</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/iphone-7-plus-review-is-it-still-usable-in-2023/"><![CDATA[<p>Hey guys, I’m Batuhan and I’ve been using an 128 GB iPhone 7 Plus as my daily driver since January of this year and in this post I’m going to talk about my experiences with it.</p>

<p>I actually wasn’t planning to get this phone. I was using my good old Galaxy Note 3 running Android 4.4.2 as my daily driver and I was happy with it.  Becouse only thing I needed was a minimal phone that gets my job done and runs everything I needed. But this is topic of another post and in future I’m planning to make a review on that phone but I’ve lost the one I had at the earthquake and now I have to find one in working condition which isn’t an easy task. But hopefully when I found one, I’ll make a post about it too. Enough talking lets start with 7 Plus.</p>

<h2 id="my-setup-and-usage">My Setup and usage:</h2>
<p><img src="https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/789025765055791104/1102337116727414904/IMG_1976.PNG" alt="Homescreen" />
I have a single page setup with all the apps and widgets I need becouse I want to keep this phone minimal and less distractive as possible. 
<img src="https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/789025765055791104/1102337117373350058/IMG_1979.PNG" alt="App Library" />
“Minimal and non distractive phone”
I mostly use this phone for note taking over Evernote, reading the latest from the RSS feeds I follow using the NetNewsWire, taking some good looking photos using Camera, editing them on Lightroom and uploading to my Nextcloud server and spending some free time over social media apps like Instagram [yes I do use instagram becouse all my friends do and it’s the only place where I could talk to them] and Mastodon. And it does all of these tasks great with no problems. But there is a optimization problem with the Evernote app and it needs to be fixed. What I mean by that, the app runs perfectly fine when it’s offline but it lags so bad when I try to type something while it’s online. I don’t know what is the reason of that but this problem only exists with the iPhone 7 Plus and I hope they’ll fix it as soon as possible.</p>

<h2 id="battery">Battery:</h2>
<p><img src="https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/789025765055791104/1102337117767602277/IMG_1988.PNG" alt="" />
Given at it’s age, this phones battery isn’t in the best condition. It’s at %74 and sometimes leaves me at half a day. But most of the time I go outside, I do keep my wirelles connections like LTE, WiFi and Bluetooth and that helps battery to stay for the entire day with no problem.</p>

<h2 id="camera">Camera:</h2>
<p>Back in the August of 2016, when this phone has released. Dual camera of this phone was revolutionary. It was the first dual camera phone on the market and being able to shoot portrait photos with natural blur and video recording at 4k 30fps which was never seen on a mobile device like that before and created a very big hype that still controls the mobile phone market today. And I think that camera of this phone isn’t old yet and still be able to take great looking pictures under daylight. But when it comes to nighttime camera of this phone starts to struggle. Here is some photos I took with this phone to show the difference between daylight and nightlight.</p>
<h3 id="my-old-iphone-6-plus">My old iPhone 6 Plus</h3>
<p><img src="https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/789025765055791104/1102338159678869605/IMG_0119.png" alt="Daylight with portrait on my hand" /> <img src="https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/789025765055791104/1102338160614178909/IMG_0123.png" alt="Nightlight with portraint under a tree" /></p>

<h3 id="portraits">Portraits</h3>
<p><img src="https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/789025765055791104/1102338158936465548/IMG_0091.png" alt="My friend Yusuf with portrait mode at daylight" /> <img src="https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/789025765055791104/1102337939771494560/IMG_0332.png" alt="My tiny brother Doğukan with portrait at nightlight" />
As you can see from photos, light really creates a day and night difference both on portrait and normal photos. But I think that it does a better job than most of the 2016 phones under nightlight.</p>

<h2 id="final-troughs">Final troughs:</h2>
<p>So in the end, if you ask me that is this phone is still usable my answer is will be yes. Becouse since it haven’t lost it’s support yet every single app that you could think of still works perfectly fine over there and I never encountered any problems with the performance of this phone. So like if you want to get into Apple ecosystem and wanna start with something cheap or you need an iPhone for your little brother or an old member of your family so you can send iMessage or Facetime with them you can prefer this phone with no doubt. One of these on good condition like mine could last at least 4 years and I think that it’s enough for a phones life.</p>

<p>Thanks for checking out with this post, if you have any questions or suggestions, you can always send me an e-mail over at <a href="batuhan@thebatuhansnetwork.xyz">mailto://</a> or join our <a href="https://discord.com/invite/5p27ZdzQzF">Discord server</a> and our tiny community!</p>

<h2 id="thank-you">Thank You!</h2>

<p>Batuhan Yılmaz - 30.04.2023 - 13/100</p>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>batuhan@thebatuhansnetwork.xyz</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey guys, I’m Batuhan and I’ve been using an 128 GB iPhone 7 Plus as my daily driver since January of this year and in this post I’m going to talk about my experiences with it.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I created a backup site over at Github Pages</title><link href="http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/i-created-a-backup-site/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I created a backup site over at Github Pages" /><published>2023-04-23T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-04-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/i-created-a-backup-site</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/i-created-a-backup-site/"><![CDATA[<p>So you may notice that my blog site was down for the last 2 or 3 weeks and this was mostly becouse some of my things wasn’t going right on it’s way and I had to shut my server down to keep up but now I came back and decided to create a backup website over at Github Pages under the <a href="https://blog.thebatuhansnetwork.xyz">blog</a> subdomain. So if my main site is down, I could easly forward my main domain to this subdomain and keep my followers like you on my site. Soon I’ll migrate my server to a virtual machine running on a different server in a different location and this way I won’t have a need for something like that.</p>

<p>If you have any ideas you can always email me at<a href="mailto://batuhan@thebatuhansnetwork.xyz">batuhan@thebatuhansnetwork.xyz </a> address and I’ll try to respond fast as possible.</p>

<h2 id="thank-you">Thank You!</h2>

<p>Batuhan Yılmaz - 23.04.2023 - 12/100</p>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>batuhan@thebatuhansnetwork.xyz</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So you may notice that my blog site was down for the last 2 or 3 weeks and this was mostly becouse some of my things wasn’t going right on it’s way and I had to shut my server down to keep up but now I came back and decided to create a backup website over at Github Pages under the blog subdomain. So if my main site is down, I could easly forward my main domain to this subdomain and keep my followers like you on my site. Soon I’ll migrate my server to a virtual machine running on a different server in a different location and this way I won’t have a need for something like that.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">10th post of #100DaysToOffload</title><link href="http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/10th-post-of-100daystooffload/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="10th post of #100DaysToOffload" /><published>2023-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/10th-post-of-100daystooffload</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/10th-post-of-100daystooffload/"><![CDATA[<p>So yeah. This is the 10th post of the 2023 and the <a href="https://100daystooffload.com">#100DaysToOffload</a>challenge and to be honest it was way harder than I expected when I started that challenge. I was planning to reach to that milestone at the middle of the Febuary but as we all know, huge disasters has happened and recovering from that wasn’t an easy thing to do.</p>

<p>But yeah let’s throw the past away and continue from where we left of from. Becouse turning back to these days over and over again never helps and just makes recovering harder and harder.</p>

<p>Hopefully guys I’ll continue to write into my blog and we’ll reach to the 25th post, 50th post and as the end of this year the 100th post. Anyways guys thanks for reading. See you in the next post.</p>

<h2 id="thank-you">Thank You!</h2>

<p>Batuhan Yılmaz - 21.03.2023 - 10/100</p>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>batuhan@thebatuhansnetwork.xyz</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So yeah. This is the 10th post of the 2023 and the #100DaysToOffloadchallenge and to be honest it was way harder than I expected when I started that challenge. I was planning to reach to that milestone at the middle of the Febuary but as we all know, huge disasters has happened and recovering from that wasn’t an easy thing to do.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Migrating server went wrong</title><link href="http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/migrating-server-went-wrong/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Migrating server went wrong" /><published>2023-03-20T20:01:28+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-20T20:01:28+00:00</updated><id>http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/migrating-server-went-wrong</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/migrating-server-went-wrong/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone I’m Batuhan. 2 days ago I decided to migrate my new server’s 80 GB OS HDD into a 32 GB USB 3.0 drive and even tho migration has finished without any problems but since we aren’t livin in the perfect world. It created lots of problems and I had to reverse it and now the site you’re currently in works from that HDD. Let’s hope into details.
The idea of doing this migration isn’t actually new. I had that idea since the day I got this server. Becouse Hdd of this server is an OEM Seagate Barracuda 80 GB drive from January of 2010 and at the time I got this server it had total of 38K hours of runtimes and 2 days ago this number was about to hit to the 39K. Actually drive works perfectly fine. I never encountered any problems with it. Since its most I/O tasks are done while the server boots and it just idles most of it’s uptimes. But since this drive is an 13 years old drive it just scares me. To fix that not existing problem I was thinking about doing a whole reinstall of the Debian 11 on that USB drive and start from fresh on my server which I already did 5 weeks ago lol. Than I gave up from that idea becouse reconfiguring things and most importantly the RAID 1 isn’t a thing I would like to do and for that I decided to clone the OS drive and continue from where I left before. But sonce I said earlier we aren’t living in the perfect awesome world and things always goes wrong.
The migration progress went perfectly fine. To do the migration I booted up my laptop and ssh’d into server, than used dd to create an image of the HDD and after getting the image I used the gzip to compress it. I used <a href="https://wiki.archlinux.org/title/Dd">this wiki page</a> as an referance on Ach wiki to do that. Please be carefull when using DD on your own machine.
After getting the image and compression progress is done. I copied the image to my Laptop using Nautilus (Yes I used a GUi program instead of scp command line. I don’t use Arch btw.) While the imaging the drive, I downloaded the Clonezilla-live and created a VM with it. After that I mounted my Ventoy USB, Clonezilla LiveCD, the USB drive I’m gonna use for the OS and the image I just got from my server into the virtual machine and booted it. Before migrating anything I had to do some changes on the image. Becouse the image was to big for my 32GB USB and that scares the clonezilla. For that I booted the Fedora 38 pre-release from the Ventoy USB and changed the partitions of the image. I removed the swap and resized the root partition to 26 GB and it went perfectly fine. After that I booted up the CloneZilla Live and cloned the image to the USB drive. Until that actually everything went perfectly fine. But the problems started when I try to boot the USB on my server.</p>

<h3 id="problem-1">Problem 1:</h3>

<p>So the first problem I encountered is mdadm. First thing that showed up when I booted up my server was mdadm wasn’t detecting my RAID 1 and becouse of that fstab was failing to mount the RAID volume and OS wasn’t booting. To investigate the problem on the OS side I shutdown the server and plugged that USB back to my laptop and edited the fstab and commented it out. And after that it booted just fine if we don’t mind the mdadm errors.</p>

<h3 id="problem-2">Problem 2</h3>

<p>The second and the biggest problem was the server was slow. In any terms it was very slow. For some reason when I boot the USB on my Laptop via the USB 3.0 port it runs perfectly fine but on server it was slow as hell. And that was leading systemD to go crazy. Booting it up were takes 2 minutes and even logging on over the TtY were almost impossible. It was leading the OS to crash after waiting for 5 minutes.</p>

<p>These were the 2 problem I was having and since I already had 3 days of downtime I wanted to give up on it and just keep a backup of the drive on my laptop and do a reinstall of the OS when it’s time has come. But for now it works perfectly fine and on programming world we have term. If it works, don’t fix it.  And this is what I’m going to do.</p>

<h2 id="thank-you">Thank You!</h2>

<p>Batuhan Yılmaz - 21.03.2023 - 9/100</p>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz &lt;batuhan@thebatuhansnetwork.xyz&gt;</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello everyone I’m Batuhan. 2 days ago I decided to migrate my new server’s 80 GB OS HDD into a 32 GB USB 3.0 drive and even tho migration has finished without any problems but since we aren’t livin in the perfect world. It created lots of problems and I had to reverse it and now the site you’re currently in works from that HDD. Let’s hope into details. The idea of doing this migration isn’t actually new. I had that idea since the day I got this server. Becouse Hdd of this server is an OEM Seagate Barracuda 80 GB drive from January of 2010 and at the time I got this server it had total of 38K hours of runtimes and 2 days ago this number was about to hit to the 39K. Actually drive works perfectly fine. I never encountered any problems with it. Since its most I/O tasks are done while the server boots and it just idles most of it’s uptimes. But since this drive is an 13 years old drive it just scares me. To fix that not existing problem I was thinking about doing a whole reinstall of the Debian 11 on that USB drive and start from fresh on my server which I already did 5 weeks ago lol. Than I gave up from that idea becouse reconfiguring things and most importantly the RAID 1 isn’t a thing I would like to do and for that I decided to clone the OS drive and continue from where I left before. But sonce I said earlier we aren’t living in the perfect awesome world and things always goes wrong. The migration progress went perfectly fine. To do the migration I booted up my laptop and ssh’d into server, than used dd to create an image of the HDD and after getting the image I used the gzip to compress it. I used this wiki page as an referance on Ach wiki to do that. Please be carefull when using DD on your own machine. After getting the image and compression progress is done. I copied the image to my Laptop using Nautilus (Yes I used a GUi program instead of scp command line. I don’t use Arch btw.) While the imaging the drive, I downloaded the Clonezilla-live and created a VM with it. After that I mounted my Ventoy USB, Clonezilla LiveCD, the USB drive I’m gonna use for the OS and the image I just got from my server into the virtual machine and booted it. Before migrating anything I had to do some changes on the image. Becouse the image was to big for my 32GB USB and that scares the clonezilla. For that I booted the Fedora 38 pre-release from the Ventoy USB and changed the partitions of the image. I removed the swap and resized the root partition to 26 GB and it went perfectly fine. After that I booted up the CloneZilla Live and cloned the image to the USB drive. Until that actually everything went perfectly fine. But the problems started when I try to boot the USB on my server.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I’m on diff.blog now!</title><link href="http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/im-on-diffblog-now/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I’m on diff.blog now!" /><published>2023-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/im-on-diffblog-now</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/im-on-diffblog-now/"><![CDATA[<p>After being away for some time. I’m back again. I decided to publish my blogsite over the places like <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com">Hacker News</a> and <a href="https://diff.blog">diff.blog</a> and this is beginning of that. Hopefully things will go as expected and I’ll publish more and more blogposts over the time. I still want to accomplish the <a href="https://100daystooffload.com">#100DaysToOffload</a> challenge and this is the 8th post since the day I started. I still have plenty of time left so lets go.</p>

<h2 id="thank-you">Thank you!</h2>

<p>Batuhan Yılmaz - 09.03.2023 - 8/100</p>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>batuhan@thebatuhansnetwork.xyz</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[After being away for some time. I’m back again. I decided to publish my blogsite over the places like Hacker News and diff.blog and this is beginning of that. Hopefully things will go as expected and I’ll publish more and more blogposts over the time. I still want to accomplish the #100DaysToOffload challenge and this is the 8th post since the day I started. I still have plenty of time left so lets go.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My messed up mind</title><link href="http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/my-messed-up-mind/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My messed up mind" /><published>2023-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/my-messed-up-mind</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/my-messed-up-mind/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone, I’m Batuhan and greetings from another day with my messed up mind and it’s messed up ideas and stuff.</p>

<p>Since the day we had that earthquakes, everyday I do loose my mind more and more guys what I mean by that is before that earthquake I had great ideas inside my head and was planning to make them real.
The 5th Febuary was a great day it was a sunny day on the Malatya and the school was about to start on it’s exiting new season. At the last hours of that night I was planned everything perfectly on and wrote them onto my notebook. The notebook that I was writing my stuff before putting them into Evernote and stuff. Everything was great and at 11pm we all got our beds and had a sleep. That sleep was the worst sleep I ever got. I wasn’t know it’s reason until the 04:17 am comes. I woke up every 30 minutes for no reason and had a small amount of fear inside. I woke up for one last time. I remember it very detailed, it was 04:07 I woke up get to kitchen and drank a bottle of glass and than get into my bed and started to look my phone. And than I started to hear a noise. A noise that increases and moments later the earthquake has began. It wasn’t big at the begginning but than it got bigger and bigger and bigger and bigger and it kept getting bigger and bigger until it ends. Our walls and stuff has fell of at that first strike and building stayed in it’s place. After that we quickly left the building and got into our car. And than a second one happened, it was smaller than the first one but it was enough for our building and some surrounding buildings to collapse… I just don’t want to continue on that. We were just happy for that we were survived and left the building on time. Than we left the city, moved into Nevşehir and I’m still up and running.</p>

<p>After that disaster I got addicted to things like watching Youtube videos, Instagram Reels and etc… I don’t have any energy to do anything like even writing this blogpost guys. I normally write this out in like 1 hour but it took me 3 days to write and publish this post. Becouse my mind is just a pile of nothing these days, I do feel like a computer that’s running without a CPU installed. I don’t know how to overcome this situation and I really need help for that. Hopefully I’ll write another blogpost soon that says I got recovered and happy the old Batuhan is back! But for now I’m just there standing with nothing. Just a body without a working brain.</p>

<p>That was it guys. I just wanted to update that 1 reader of my blog. As I said I’m still trying to recover in a safe and secure place. If you want to help me you can always send me a mail over the <a href="mailto://batuhan@thebatuhansnetwork.xyz">batuhan@thebatuhansnetwork.xyz</a> address and maybe <a href="https://www.buymeacoffee.com/bthyilmaz">buy me a coffee</a> any help would be apriciated. As always see you in the next blogpost!</p>

<h2 id="thank-you">Thank You!</h2>

<p>Batuhan Yılmaz - 02.03.2023 - 7/100</p>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>batuhan@thebatuhansnetwork.xyz</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello everyone, I’m Batuhan and greetings from another day with my messed up mind and it’s messed up ideas and stuff.]]></summary></entry></feed>