<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" /><updated>2023-01-20T20:38:51+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Batuhan’s Blog</title><subtitle>The Batuhan's Blog</subtitle><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>bthyilmaz@outlook.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Using an iPhone 6 Plus as a secondary phone in 2023</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/using-an-iphone-6-plus-as-a-secondary-phone-in-2023/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using an iPhone 6 Plus as a secondary phone in 2023" /><published>2023-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/using-an-iphone-6-plus-as-a-secondary-phone-in-2023</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/using-an-iphone-6-plus-as-a-secondary-phone-in-2023/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone, I’m Batuhan and this blogpost has written from my new iPhone 6 Plus! I’ve got this phone from my cousin and it’s been used ver carefully and it runs pretty great. And for that I wanted see how it holds up trough a day and for that I carried it with me to the school and it made trough the day without any big problems. Only problem that I had with this phone is it has a defective battery in it and it doesn’t lasts long. Like since the beginning of the test, I had to plug it in for 3 times and charge it up up to 80 percent in order to keep that thing up. Otherwise it works perfectly fine for almost any tasks. Like writing this blogpost on the Evernote app, taking some photos using the camera or listening music trough the Apple Music. 
<img src="https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/789025765055791104/1066087440877637703/IMG_0010.PNG" alt="iPhone's battery health" />
Like as you can see on the screenshot that I put there the battery life isn’t good and it could shut itself down even on %60 but I think this is also because that phone was in it’s box since the summer of 2020 and batter could be degraded because of that and I think it’ll fix itself after some charge cycles. Also becouse of these shutdowns the phone put itself into a mode named “Peak performace” and becouse of that it runs slower than it should. But it’s an easy fix. Just replace the battery and it’s back on the roads with full performance. But for now I’m not planning to do it</p>

<p>Another problem this phone has is it’s 16 GB of storage. This phone only has 16 GBs of storage space and 4 GB of it is already filled up by the iOS 12. Which leaves me only 12 GBs of usable storage and after installing like 7 app that I use daily it fills the half of it’s usable storage. If you’re the one who only uses his phone for phone calls and never installs any other apps than Whatsapp, than there is plenty of empty storage for you. But not for me.
<img src="https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/789025765055791104/1066086733931876372/IMG_0012.PNG" alt="iPhone Storage usage" />
As you can see over there I already filled the half if it’s storage space and there is only my music and some apps and it’s half full already I don’t even have the quarter of the things that I have on my 128 GB iPhone 7 Plus. Which I already filled up the 40 GB of this space lol.
<img src="https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/789025765055791104/1066087802606989403/IMG_0014.PNG" alt="HomeScreen of the iPhone 6 Plus" />
As you can see there is only 8 apps and 98 music not a single photo on my gallery (expect the iCloud photos which aren’t saved locally on my phone). This is the only problem that I haven’t with this phone as I said. Otherwise this phone is a very nice phone and still usable after all these years. It’a still fast and well supported when age of this phone is considered. And I do believe that this phone would became a better phone with some jailbreaking and a battery swap. In future I’ll try to make this phone a better phone but for now I don’t have the enough time and money to do the things I planned.</p>

<p>So this was a simple blogpost that I wrote after using it as my second phone for a day. I’m planning to only use this phone as my daily driver and make a longer and detailed blogpost about how it’s usable and using it with some jailbreak tweaks. Also I’m gonna write a blogpost about my 7 Plus too but for now I don’t have much free time to sit on my computer and write blogposts. So sorry for that.  But I’m generally updating my <a href="https://fosstodon.org/@B4tuhanY1lmaz">Fosstodon account</a>. You can always come and follow me over there. Also don’t forget to join our Discord server if you’re looking for somewhere to hang up.</p>

<h1 id="thank-you">Thank You!</h1>

<p>Batuhan Yılmaz - 20.01.2023</p>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>bthyilmaz@outlook.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello everyone, I’m Batuhan and this blogpost has written from my new iPhone 6 Plus! I’ve got this phone from my cousin and it’s been used ver carefully and it runs pretty great. And for that I wanted see how it holds up trough a day and for that I carried it with me to the school and it made trough the day without any big problems. Only problem that I had with this phone is it has a defective battery in it and it doesn’t lasts long. Like since the beginning of the test, I had to plug it in for 3 times and charge it up up to 80 percent in order to keep that thing up. Otherwise it works perfectly fine for almost any tasks. Like writing this blogpost on the Evernote app, taking some photos using the camera or listening music trough the Apple Music. Like as you can see on the screenshot that I put there the battery life isn’t good and it could shut itself down even on %60 but I think this is also because that phone was in it’s box since the summer of 2020 and batter could be degraded because of that and I think it’ll fix itself after some charge cycles. Also becouse of these shutdowns the phone put itself into a mode named “Peak performace” and becouse of that it runs slower than it should. But it’s an easy fix. Just replace the battery and it’s back on the roads with full performance. But for now I’m not planning to do it]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Here comes 2023. What do I expect?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/here-comes-the-2023-what-do-i-expect/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Here comes 2023. What do I expect?" /><published>2022-12-31T01:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-12-31T01:30:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/here-comes-the-2023-what-do-i-expect</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/here-comes-the-2023-what-do-i-expect/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone, I’m Batuhan Yılmaz and as we all know another year has come to it’s end. With it’s good sides and bad sides it was a good year for me, becouse recovering from the global pandemic and turning back to schools and the social life after 2 years of lockdown was a huge plus for me.  With it’s good sides and bad sides it was a good year.</p>

<h2 id="what-do-i-expect-from-the-2023">What do I expect from the 2023?</h2>

<p>So yeah a complete new year and of course things will change a bit, but I’m not into that “A new year a new me” shit becouse we all know that most of us doesn’t gets their new year plans done. 
So all I expect from the 2023 is just succsess on the final year of the highschool. Becouse in June 2023, I’ll take an exam to attend my dream college and become a college-graduated software engineer. We all know that everyone looking for a Carbon Developer that has 10 years of experience and gradue from Harvard. And becouse of that I have to work hard and get into that college.  Other than that I just expect another good year like 2022.</p>

<h2 id="acknowledge-of-2022">Acknowledge of 2022</h2>

<p>As my last words of 2022, I want to say thanks to everyone who made 2022 an awesome year for me. I really can’t imagine how 2022 would’ve been without them. I’m not just talking about the people I talk to in my life. I’m also talking about the people on my Discord server. You guys are just awesome in every way, and I want to thank you for making the last two years of my life  awesome! I wish you all have the best in 2023.</p>

<h2 id="one-more-thing">One more thing</h2>

<p>As one more thing, I asked ChatGPT to write a blogpost about new year and here’s the result:</p>

<p><img src="https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/789025765055791104/1058767628962893874/chrome_SB5SsnTrZP.png" alt="ChatGPT Answer" /></p>
<h2 id="thank-you">Thank You.</h2>
<p>Batuhan Yılmaz - 31.12.22</p>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>bthyilmaz@outlook.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello everyone, I’m Batuhan Yılmaz and as we all know another year has come to it’s end. With it’s good sides and bad sides it was a good year for me, becouse recovering from the global pandemic and turning back to schools and the social life after 2 years of lockdown was a huge plus for me. With it’s good sides and bad sides it was a good year.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Here goes the November 2022</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/here-goes-the-november-2022/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Here goes the November 2022" /><published>2022-11-30T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-11-30T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/here-goes-the-november-2022</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/here-goes-the-november-2022/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone I’m Batuhan Yılmaz.
It’s been long time since last time I publish something to my blog. 5 months since my last post and some stuff has been changed since then.  Like the way I host this blog, the look and feel, the city I’m in and etc. I’m not gonna talk about them for now becouse they’re topic for anpther blogpost. The reason why I didn’t published anything is actually becouse I don’t have mcuh free time for writing up.  I become a 12th grade student in Turkey and the achievements I’ll get this year is so important for the university that I’ll go. And as we all know a good university means a good carrier and if I want to be a Software engineer with a good salary then I have to work hard this year. Anyway back to topic. The reason for this blogpost was just to inform the 1 person who reads my post that I’m maintaining this website.🙂</p>

<h2 id="one-more-thing">One more thing</h2>

<ul>
  <li>I know this header may sound exiting but actually it’s not really much. As you guys know, I do selfhost this webpage and my server don’t gets the best uptimes and for that I decided to use the <a href="https://codeberg.page">Codeberg Pages</a> as a backup site under the blog subdomain and use the main domain for the main site. Hopefully it will be a better solution as a backup.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="thank-you">Thank You.</h2>

<ul>
  <li>Batuhan Yılmaz - 30.11.22</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>bthyilmaz@outlook.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello everyone I’m Batuhan Yılmaz. It’s been long time since last time I publish something to my blog. 5 months since my last post and some stuff has been changed since then. Like the way I host this blog, the look and feel, the city I’m in and etc. I’m not gonna talk about them for now becouse they’re topic for anpther blogpost. The reason why I didn’t published anything is actually becouse I don’t have mcuh free time for writing up. I become a 12th grade student in Turkey and the achievements I’ll get this year is so important for the university that I’ll go. And as we all know a good university means a good carrier and if I want to be a Software engineer with a good salary then I have to work hard this year. Anyway back to topic. The reason for this blogpost was just to inform the 1 person who reads my post that I’m maintaining this website.🙂]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I’m using an Hackintosh for 6 months. Now what?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/im-using-an-hackintosh-for-6-months-now-what/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I’m using an Hackintosh for 6 months. Now what?" /><published>2022-06-23T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-06-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/im-using-an-hackintosh-for-6-months-now-what</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/im-using-an-hackintosh-for-6-months-now-what/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone I’m Batuhan and I’m a Linux user for the past 8 years and I’m using an hackintosh as my daily driver on desktop for 6 months. And I’m always asking myself that question: Now what? Am I gonna ditch the Linux on desktop or just gonna reinstall Fedora? Let’s talk about that.</p>

<h2 id="beginning">Beginning</h2>
<p>So the idea of hackintoshing my Dell Optiplex 7050 was a thing that I really wanted to do since the 2019, the year that I got my computer. Since then I tried hackintoshing 3 times until I got it running sucsessfully on the hardware. Before that I was using an Ivy Bridge computer with macOS High Sierra running on it with clover bootloader. And since I was knew a bit about clover and I wanted to use clover for my second hackintosh and it was unsuccessful. For some reason the OS just kept kernel panicking and I was gave up on it. Than 1 year later I found out that a bootloader named OpenCore exist and I wanted to try it for a second time. And the result of it was better. I was able to get the installation screen and I was able to install macOS Catalina into the HDD and it was working fine. Until I realized that the GPU acceleration wasn’t working on either iGPU or dGPU. So in there I was gaved up second time. And after doing some research I found out that a guy got macOS running perfectly fine on his Dell Optiplex 7050 Micro which doesn’t have much difference than the tower which I have. So I started to working on his EFI and after tweaking it a bit I was able to fix the GPU problem that I had and was able to run Catalina perfectly fine. Than I tried upgrading the OS like a real mac and it ran pretty well. I was able to upgrade to the Monterey from Cataling and I didn’t had to change anything on the EFI side. I was too happy about that becouse not just I got it working without any problem, I was got an Unix based OS which could run some of the Linux apps that I was using a lot via the Macports and can run the properitary Adobe programs that I need soo much becouse of our video projects.</p>

<h2 id="what-im-gonna-do-in-future">What I’m gonna do in future?</h2>
<p>So as you know the next release of the macOS named Ventura got announced and cut support for lot’s of devices. So the good side is it’s compatible with my hardware and the SMBIOS I do use so I can upgrade it. But I’m not gonna upgrade to the Ventura anytime soon. Even if it becomes stable. The reason for this is becouse there is not a real difference between these 2 versions of the OS. And there is always the risk of breaking a working system which I don’t really want to do. But when the patchers for the old hardware comes out I’ll try to get it running on my old computer which has a Intel Core I5-3570K CPU in it.</p>

<h2 id="what-im-doing-with-my-hackintosh">What I’m doing with my Hackintosh?</h2>
<p>So let’s come to the question that’s important for me. What I’m doing with my computer. So the main thing is I do play games like OSU!, Minecraft, CIV6 and Terraria ,doing video editing a lot. Like I do have 3 different video editing software installed on my computer and I do use 2 of them a lot. These are the KDEnlive and Adobe Premiere PRO. Since I know both of these software I do use them. KDEnlive for basic video editing like cutting videos, merging videos or just adding a background music to them. And using Adobe Premiere PRO for advenced tasks. And virtualizing stuff with the UTM APP and QEMU. Otherwise I’m mostly using it for web browsing and my computer really does these tasks really well.</p>

<p>Also I want to point a thing that most people online just loves to judge these Dell Optiplex users and says “Oh do you have a Optiplex man my toaster is more powerfull than your computer”. I know most people not gonna think same with me but I believe that these computers are really fast and powerful computers if you use them in the right configration. Like using custom AMD GPU drivers named NimeZ on Windows 10 really unlocks the potential of the stock GPU that computer comes with.</p>

<h2 id="now-what">Now what?</h2>
<p>So as I asked on the header of that post is “Now what?” So I’ll keep it using until I decide to switch back to Linux on my desktop. But until that I’m going to keep it on the macOS Monterey and use it for my daily bases and if I do need a Linux environment runs on bare metal hardware, I can just use my server for that. It has the complete same hardware in it expect the storage side and I even used it while building the EFI and it helped me a lot while tinkering stuff.  So even if I need Linux I don’t need to install it.</p>

<h2 id="should-you-create-a-hackintosh">Should you create a hackintosh?</h2>
<p>So if you gonna ask me that question my answer will be no, unless you have free time and want to mess up with your hardware. But why I said no? Becouse believe or not building an hackintosh needs a lot of time and passion. It doesn’t ends with just installing the OS, you need to do lot’s of testing after installing OS, like getting the sleep working, mapping your USB ports, getting wifi and bluetooth working and etc. It needs lot’s of time and tinkering to get it running stable as a real mac.  You don’t have to do these stuff or have to tinker that much on even installing Gentoo, I’m serious about that. If you need a computer for production I just suggest you to go and install either Windows or Linux. But even ef you want to do an hackintosh than good luck man, just make sure you have an extra computer while working on your hackintosh.</p>

<p>Thanks for reading that blog post. This was a post that I really wanted to share with you for long time. If you want to build a hackintosh or discuss about technology, please join our <a href="https://discord.gg/jt5wXUKa">Discord server</a> !</p>

<h1 id="thank-you">Thank You!</h1>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>bthyilmaz@outlook.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello everyone I’m Batuhan and I’m a Linux user for the past 8 years and I’m using an hackintosh as my daily driver on desktop for 6 months. And I’m always asking myself that question: Now what? Am I gonna ditch the Linux on desktop or just gonna reinstall Fedora? Let’s talk about that.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Configuring Jekyll</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/configuring-jekyll/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Configuring Jekyll" /><published>2022-06-16T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-06-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/configuring-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/configuring-jekyll/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone I’m Batuhan and today I’m going to talk about how I configured my Jekyll Blog from it’s stock look and feel to the current look and feel.</p>

<h2 id="installing-jekyll-and-its-plugins">Installing Jekyll and it’s plugins</h2>
<p>Firstly you need to install Jekyll according to the documention. <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/docs/installation/ubuntu/">Jekyll on Ubuntu | Jekyll • Simple, blog-aware, static sites</a> Since I’m using Ubuntu Server I linked the one for Ubuntu but it could work on other Debian based distros. Than I installed the<a href="https://github.com/tocttou/hacker-blog">GitHub - tocttou/hacker-blog</a> theme by cloning it into a folder and configuring the _config.yml file.</p>
<h3 id="plugins">Plugins</h3>
<p>Of course I’m using couple of plugins to improve the Jekyll experience.
These are the</p>
<ul>
  <li>Jekyll SEO tag</li>
  <li>Jekyll Admin</li>
  <li>Jekyll Sitemap</li>
  <li>Jekyll Paginate
I’m using these plugins for improving the blog and creating posts easier. The Admin plugin is generally disabled because of the security flaws that it has but when creating posts I’m enabling it, creating post and disabling it.</li>
</ul>

<p>This was basically an easy thing to setup as I want. Now let’s talk about why I’m not hosting that website on a GitHub pages and using my own server.
So basically hosting stuff on my own server is always better than hosting it somewhere online. But I’m gonna host a backup on Github pages too. Because my server could be unreliable sometimes and having a backup on Github is always a nice thing.</p>

<h2 id="how-i-setup-the-server-side">How I setup the server side</h2>
<p>So lets come to the most important part. Most people online has setup their server using ngix web server but I already have a Apache2 server setup and I don’t want to mess up with my server by setting up another web server or trying to get Apache working while breaking other websites. So for that I just used the Jekyll’s built in server function and systemd. 
But in there I had to install every GEM that I installed on my user on the root user to get the systemd serivce working. Otherwise it would show as working but in journals Ruby just spams a lot of can’t find gem errors. But it works now and here is the system.service file that I used for my setup:</p>
<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>[Unit]
Description=Jekyll
After=cloudflared.service # Staring it after cloudflared. You can change that.
[Service]
User=&lt;user&gt; # You need to replace it with the user that you want to run your blog.
TimeoutStartSec=0
Type=notify
WorkingDirectory=&lt;directory of your blog&gt;
ExecStart=/home/&lt;user&gt;/gems/bin/jekyll serve #The Jekyll executable that's located in your users home folder. You have to change that tho.
Restart=on-failure
RestartSec=10s

[Install]
WantedBy=multi-user.target
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>It was that simple and hopefully it works for you too. But always there is a chance of a thing that works for me not works for you. So in that situation you can come to our <a href="https://discord.gg/jt5wXUKa">Discord server</a> and get help from there.</p>

<h3 id="thank-you">Thank You.</h3>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>bthyilmaz@outlook.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello everyone I’m Batuhan and today I’m going to talk about how I configured my Jekyll Blog from it’s stock look and feel to the current look and feel.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Creating a new blog site. How I created it?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/creating-a-new-blog-site-how-i-created-it/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Creating a new blog site. How I created it?" /><published>2022-06-15T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-06-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/creating-a-new-blog-site-how-i-created-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/creating-a-new-blog-site-how-i-created-it/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone! This is Batuhan and this is the first post of my new blog.</p>

<h3 id="but-why">But why?</h3>
<p>This is a perfect question because I don’t have an proper answer for that. What I mean is I always wanted to have a blog site that’s easy to deploy and doesn’t needs lots of work to make something looks good. 
Another answer is: I love logging what I’m doing and sharing that with other people who interested on the same topic with me. 
Firstly I was considered the Google Blogpost  as a blog site but than I realised that it would be harder to do that using it because it doesn’t have good themes as the Jekyll does and not so easy to configure it. Than I started to host my own services at 22 March 2022 and with that I started to consider creating my own blog website. But at that time I wasn’t knew about the Jekyll and I was thinking about hiring a web developer and paying that guy like hundrends or thousands of dollars to just have a simple blog website that has a good backend. Than I came across	with some blog sites and some documentation sites of Open source is using a thing named “Jekyll” to create these web sites and than I started to do some research about it and this is where I’m right now. I started to a journey with that and hopefully that journey will last</p>
<h3 id="how-i-created-that-website-with-lots-of-limitations-from-my-isp">How I created that website with lot’s of limitations from my ISP?</h3>
<p>Now this is a question that I really want to answer a lot because my ISP doesn’t gives us IPv6 addresses and uses IPv4 with CG-NAT. Which makes opening a port impossible and they sell static IP’s for expensive prices and it’s really not worth to pay for it. So while I was doing researches about cheap VPS provider and I was about to pay Linode 5$/mo to just bridge my connection to a server that I don’t even know who can access to it. Than I started to look into other things like Ngrok but the problem with these stuff you had to use their domain for your website if you don’t want to pay for it. Than I came across with CloudFlareD tunnel. It was like finding Diamonds while mining hopelessly on Minecraft. It had everything that I wanted. It was free, I could use my own domain which I paid for it and most importantly it had features like ddos protection and other stuff. So I started to deploy my stuff on a Ivy Bridge era computer using Ubuntu Server 20.04. And it’s been 3 months now and I didn’t had any problems with it.</p>
<h3 id="how-i-created-that-website-">How I created that website ?</h3>
<p>So only thing that I had to do is setting up the Jekyll package as the documentation suggests. <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/docs/">Quickstart | Jekyll • Simple, blog-aware, static sites</a> And that’s it. It’s ready for production.</p>

<p>So this was my first blogpost on my new blog and thanks for reading and joining to my journey with me. Please do not forget to join our Discord server<a href="https://discord.gg/jt5wXUKa">The Batuhan’s Network</a>!</p>

<h2 id="thank-you">Thank You!</h2>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>bthyilmaz@outlook.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello everyone! This is Batuhan and this is the first post of my new blog.]]></summary></entry></feed>