<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" /><updated>2023-03-21T17:02:02+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Batuhan’s Blog</title><subtitle>The Batuhan's Blog</subtitle><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>bthyilmaz@outlook.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">10th post of #100DaysToOffload</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/10th-post-of-100daystooffload/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="10th post of #100DaysToOffload" /><published>2023-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/10th-post-of-100daystooffload</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/10th-post-of-100daystooffload/"><![CDATA[<p>So yeah. This is the 10th post of the 2023 and the <a href="https://100daystooffload.com">#100DaysToOffload</a>challenge and to be honest it was way harder than I expected when I started that challenge. I was planning to reach to that milestone at the middle of the Febuary but as we all know, huge disasters has happened and recovering from that wasn’t an easy thing to do.</p>

<p>But yeah let’s throw the past away and continue from where we left of from. Becouse turning back to these days over and over again never helps and just makes recovering harder and harder.</p>

<p>Hopefully guys I’ll continue to write into my blog and we’ll reach to the 25th post, 50th post and as the end of this year the 100th post. Anyways guys thanks for reading. See you in the next post.</p>

<h2 id="thank-you">Thank You!</h2>

<p>Batuhan Yılmaz - 21.03.2023 - 10/100</p>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>bthyilmaz@outlook.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So yeah. This is the 10th post of the 2023 and the #100DaysToOffloadchallenge and to be honest it was way harder than I expected when I started that challenge. I was planning to reach to that milestone at the middle of the Febuary but as we all know, huge disasters has happened and recovering from that wasn’t an easy thing to do.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Migrating server went wrong</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/migrating-server-went-wrong/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Migrating server went wrong" /><published>2023-03-20T20:01:28+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-20T20:01:28+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/migrating-server-went-wrong</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/migrating-server-went-wrong/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone I’m Batuhan. 2 days ago I decided to migrate my new server’s 80 GB OS HDD into a 32 GB USB 3.0 drive and even tho migration has finished without any problems but since we aren’t livin in the perfect world. It created lots of problems and I had to reverse it and now the site you’re currently in works from that HDD. Let’s hope into details.
The idea of doing this migration isn’t actually new. I had that idea since the day I got this server. Becouse Hdd of this server is an OEM Seagate Barracuda 80 GB drive from January of 2010 and at the time I got this server it had total of 38K hours of runtimes and 2 days ago this number was about to hit to the 39K. Actually drive works perfectly fine. I never encountered any problems with it. Since its most I/O tasks are done while the server boots and it just idles most of it’s uptimes. But since this drive is an 13 years old drive it just scares me. To fix that not existing problem I was thinking about doing a whole reinstall of the Debian 11 on that USB drive and start from fresh on my server which I already did 5 weeks ago lol. Than I gave up from that idea becouse reconfiguring things and most importantly the RAID 1 isn’t a thing I would like to do and for that I decided to clone the OS drive and continue from where I left before. But sonce I said earlier we aren’t living in the perfect awesome world and things always goes wrong.
The migration progress went perfectly fine. To do the migration I booted up my laptop and ssh’d into server, than used dd to create an image of the HDD and after getting the image I used the gzip to compress it. I used <a href="https://wiki.archlinux.org/title/Dd">this wiki page</a> as an referance on Ach wiki to do that. Please be carefull when using DD on your own machine.
After getting the image and compression progress is done. I copied the image to my Laptop using Nautilus (Yes I used a GUi program instead of scp command line. I don’t use Arch btw.) While the imaging the drive, I downloaded the Clonezilla-live and created a VM with it. After that I mounted my Ventoy USB, Clonezilla LiveCD, the USB drive I’m gonna use for the OS and the image I just got from my server into the virtual machine and booted it. Before migrating anything I had to do some changes on the image. Becouse the image was to big for my 32GB USB and that scares the clonezilla. For that I booted the Fedora 38 pre-release from the Ventoy USB and changed the partitions of the image. I removed the swap and resized the root partition to 26 GB and it went perfectly fine. After that I booted up the CloneZilla Live and cloned the image to the USB drive. Until that actually everything went perfectly fine. But the problems started when I try to boot the USB on my server.</p>

<h3 id="problem-1">Problem 1:</h3>

<p>So the first problem I encountered is mdadm. First thing that showed up when I booted up my server was mdadm wasn’t detecting my RAID 1 and becouse of that fstab was failing to mount the RAID volume and OS wasn’t booting. To investigate the problem on the OS side I shutdown the server and plugged that USB back to my laptop and edited the fstab and commented it out. And after that it booted just fine if we don’t mind the mdadm errors.</p>

<h3 id="problem-2">Problem 2</h3>

<p>The second and the biggest problem was the server was slow. In any terms it was very slow. For some reason when I boot the USB on my Laptop via the USB 3.0 port it runs perfectly fine but on server it was slow as hell. And that was leading systemD to go crazy. Booting it up were takes 2 minutes and even logging on over the TtY were almost impossible. It was leading the OS to crash after waiting for 5 minutes.</p>

<p>These were the 2 problem I was having and since I already had 3 days of downtime I wanted to give up on it and just keep a backup of the drive on my laptop and do a reinstall of the OS when it’s time has come. But for now it works perfectly fine and on programming world we have term. If it works, don’t fix it.  And this is what I’m going to do.</p>

<h2 id="thank-you">Thank You!</h2>

<p>Batuhan Yılmaz - 21.03.2023 - 9/100</p>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz &lt;batuhan@thebatuhansnetwork.xyz&gt;</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello everyone I’m Batuhan. 2 days ago I decided to migrate my new server’s 80 GB OS HDD into a 32 GB USB 3.0 drive and even tho migration has finished without any problems but since we aren’t livin in the perfect world. It created lots of problems and I had to reverse it and now the site you’re currently in works from that HDD. Let’s hope into details. The idea of doing this migration isn’t actually new. I had that idea since the day I got this server. Becouse Hdd of this server is an OEM Seagate Barracuda 80 GB drive from January of 2010 and at the time I got this server it had total of 38K hours of runtimes and 2 days ago this number was about to hit to the 39K. Actually drive works perfectly fine. I never encountered any problems with it. Since its most I/O tasks are done while the server boots and it just idles most of it’s uptimes. But since this drive is an 13 years old drive it just scares me. To fix that not existing problem I was thinking about doing a whole reinstall of the Debian 11 on that USB drive and start from fresh on my server which I already did 5 weeks ago lol. Than I gave up from that idea becouse reconfiguring things and most importantly the RAID 1 isn’t a thing I would like to do and for that I decided to clone the OS drive and continue from where I left before. But sonce I said earlier we aren’t living in the perfect awesome world and things always goes wrong. The migration progress went perfectly fine. To do the migration I booted up my laptop and ssh’d into server, than used dd to create an image of the HDD and after getting the image I used the gzip to compress it. I used this wiki page as an referance on Ach wiki to do that. Please be carefull when using DD on your own machine. After getting the image and compression progress is done. I copied the image to my Laptop using Nautilus (Yes I used a GUi program instead of scp command line. I don’t use Arch btw.) While the imaging the drive, I downloaded the Clonezilla-live and created a VM with it. After that I mounted my Ventoy USB, Clonezilla LiveCD, the USB drive I’m gonna use for the OS and the image I just got from my server into the virtual machine and booted it. Before migrating anything I had to do some changes on the image. Becouse the image was to big for my 32GB USB and that scares the clonezilla. For that I booted the Fedora 38 pre-release from the Ventoy USB and changed the partitions of the image. I removed the swap and resized the root partition to 26 GB and it went perfectly fine. After that I booted up the CloneZilla Live and cloned the image to the USB drive. Until that actually everything went perfectly fine. But the problems started when I try to boot the USB on my server.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I’m on diff.blog now!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/im-on-diffblog-now/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I’m on diff.blog now!" /><published>2023-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/im-on-diffblog-now</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/im-on-diffblog-now/"><![CDATA[<p>After being away for some time. I’m back again. I decided to publish my blogsite over the places like <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com">Hacker News</a> and <a href="https://diff.blog">diff.blog</a> and this is beginning of that. Hopefully things will go as expected and I’ll publish more and more blogposts over the time. I still want to accomplish the <a href="https://100daystooffload.com">#100DaysToOffload</a> challenge and this is the 8th post since the day I started. I still have plenty of time left so lets go.</p>

<h2 id="thank-you">Thank you!</h2>

<p>Batuhan Yılmaz - 09.03.2023 - 8/100</p>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>bthyilmaz@outlook.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[After being away for some time. I’m back again. I decided to publish my blogsite over the places like Hacker News and diff.blog and this is beginning of that. Hopefully things will go as expected and I’ll publish more and more blogposts over the time. I still want to accomplish the #100DaysToOffload challenge and this is the 8th post since the day I started. I still have plenty of time left so lets go.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My messed up mind</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/my-messed-up-mind/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My messed up mind" /><published>2023-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/my-messed-up-mind</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/my-messed-up-mind/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone, I’m Batuhan and greetings from another day with my messed up mind and it’s messed up ideas and stuff.</p>

<p>Since the day we had that earthquakes, everyday I do loose my mind more and more guys what I mean by that is before that earthquake I had great ideas inside my head and was planning to make them real.
The 5th Febuary was a great day it was a sunny day on the Malatya and the school was about to start on it’s exiting new season. At the last hours of that night I was planned everything perfectly on and wrote them onto my notebook. The notebook that I was writing my stuff before putting them into Evernote and stuff. Everything was great and at 11pm we all got our beds and had a sleep. That sleep was the worst sleep I ever got. I wasn’t know it’s reason until the 04:17 am comes. I woke up every 30 minutes for no reason and had a small amount of fear inside. I woke up for one last time. I remember it very detailed, it was 04:07 I woke up get to kitchen and drank a bottle of glass and than get into my bed and started to look my phone. And than I started to hear a noise. A noise that increases and moments later the earthquake has began. It wasn’t big at the begginning but than it got bigger and bigger and bigger and bigger and it kept getting bigger and bigger until it ends. Our walls and stuff has fell of at that first strike and building stayed in it’s place. After that we quickly left the building and got into our car. And than a second one happened, it was smaller than the first one but it was enough for our building and some surrounding buildings to collapse… I just don’t want to continue on that. We were just happy for that we were survived and left the building on time. Than we left the city, moved into Nevşehir and I’m still up and running.</p>

<p>After that disaster I got addicted to things like watching Youtube videos, Instagram Reels and etc… I don’t have any energy to do anything like even writing this blogpost guys. I normally write this out in like 1 hour but it took me 3 days to write and publish this post. Becouse my mind is just a pile of nothing these days, I do feel like a computer that’s running without a CPU installed. I don’t know how to overcome this situation and I really need help for that. Hopefully I’ll write another blogpost soon that says I got recovered and happy the old Batuhan is back! But for now I’m just there standing with nothing. Just a body without a working brain.</p>

<p>That was it guys. I just wanted to update that 1 reader of my blog. As I said I’m still trying to recover in a safe and secure place. If you want to help me you can always send me a mail over the <a href="mailto://batuhan@thebatuhansnetwork.xyz">batuhan@thebatuhansnetwork.xyz</a> address and maybe <a href="https://www.buymeacoffee.com/bthyilmaz">buy me a coffee</a> any help would be apriciated. As always see you in the next blogpost!</p>

<h2 id="thank-you">Thank You!</h2>

<p>Batuhan Yılmaz - 02.03.2023 - 7/100</p>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>bthyilmaz@outlook.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello everyone, I’m Batuhan and greetings from another day with my messed up mind and it’s messed up ideas and stuff.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I’m back on Blogging</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/im-back-on-blogging/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I’m back on Blogging" /><published>2023-02-23T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-02-23T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/im-back-on-blogging</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/im-back-on-blogging/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone I’m Batuhan and today I can’t be more happier becouse I’ll be able to start on blogging again. So soo much thing happened in the past, huge earthquakes fallen buildings restarting my life from scratch and etc …
What matters most is me and my family is still alive and today I decided to start blogging again. I had a backup of that website on a hidden Codeberg repo and thanks to that I’m able to restart hosting this website. 
I’m just writing this tiny post to inform you guys that I’m perfectly fine and just busy with recreating my life and other stuff. I want to say thank you for anyone supports Turkey on this disaster and helps us. Without any further words. Until next time guys!</p>

<h2 id="thank-you">Thank You!</h2>
<p>Batuhan Yılmaz - 23.02.2023 - 6/100</p>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yaşar Yılmaz</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello everyone I’m Batuhan and today I can’t be more happier becouse I’ll be able to start on blogging again. So soo much thing happened in the past, huge earthquakes fallen buildings restarting my life from scratch and etc … What matters most is me and my family is still alive and today I decided to start blogging again. I had a backup of that website on a hidden Codeberg repo and thanks to that I’m able to restart hosting this website. I’m just writing this tiny post to inform you guys that I’m perfectly fine and just busy with recreating my life and other stuff. I want to say thank you for anyone supports Turkey on this disaster and helps us. Without any further words. Until next time guys!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Adding RSS feeds from other blogs to end of my posts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/adding-rss-feeds-from-other-blogs-to-end-of-my-posts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Adding RSS feeds from other blogs to end of my posts" /><published>2023-01-26T21:00:11+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-26T21:00:11+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/adding-rss-feeds-from-other-blogs-to-end-of-my-posts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/adding-rss-feeds-from-other-blogs-to-end-of-my-posts/"><![CDATA[<p>Hey guys I’m Batuhan and at the second post of this day I’m gonna talk about how I added latest posts from the RSS feeds I follow to my blog.</p>

<p><img src="https://archive.thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/Media/Images/blog/Screenshot%202023-01-26%20at%2023.58.40.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Like that. 
So to do that I used a script named openring to do that. openring is a simple script that creates webrings using the RSS feeds. It fetches the RSS feeds that you’ve provided and creates an html file that you can place  into includes folder. So let’s go a step by step on how you can do that.</p>

<h3 id="1--install-go">1 ) Install go</h3>

<p>So this script has written in go and before start using it you have to compile it using go. I’m currently on macOS and gonna show the macOS way. But if you’re on a different OS than me you can go to https://go.dev/dl/ page and download the right binary for your OS. 
I’m going to use the macPorts to install the go into my system. To install it use the command <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">sudo port install go</code> and wait for it. After that you can get into step 2.</p>

<h3 id="2--clone-openring-and-build-it">2 ) Clone openring and build it</h3>

<p>Now open your terminal again and clone the openring using the command down below.</p>
<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>git clone https://git.sr.ht/~sircmpwn/openring &amp;&amp; cd openring
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>After that command is done, run the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">go build</code> command and wait for it. After it’s done, you can continue to step 3.</p>

<h3 id="3--use-the-openring">3 ) Use the openring</h3>

<p>And here is the step that we’re going to use the openring. Using it is very simple.</p>

<p><img src="https://archive.thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/Media/Images/blog/Screenshot%202023-01-27%20at%2000.21.39.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Now in there you can see a file named in.html. This file is our template, you can edit this file for your site’s needs and have a much better look that fits into your site. Now we’re going to create a file named out.html that includes our posts using the openring. To create that file you can use the command I put down below.</p>
<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>openring \
-s https://www.joelchrono12.xyz/feed.xml \ 
-s https://andy-bell.co.uk/feed \ 
-s https://kevquirk.com/feed.xml \
&lt; in.html \
&gt; out.html 
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>This command takes the in.html, adds 3 sources I placed and outputs it as the out.html. You can change these feeds as you like these are the ones that I’ve added to my site.</p>

<p>So now it’s time to switch into jekyll part.</p>

<p>Now in order to add our webring to our Jekyll blog. This part is really simple. 
So now place the out.html file that you just created into _includes folder inside your jekyll blog and after that go to your _layouts folder and open the post.html file.  After that place the
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">% include out.html %</code> line under the main tag.</p>

<p><img src="https://archive.thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/Media/Images/blog/Screenshot%202023-01-27%20at%2000.42.42.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Like in that picture. And you’re done.</p>

<p>I hope this post helps to everyone who wants to use openring on their own blog site. I wrote that blogpost while I’m so sleepy and I’m sorry for any mistakes I had.</p>

<h2 id="thank-you">Thank You!</h2>

<p>Batuhan Yılmaz - 27.01.2023 - 5/100</p>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>bthyilmaz@outlook.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey guys I’m Batuhan and at the second post of this day I’m gonna talk about how I added latest posts from the RSS feeds I follow to my blog.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">It’s time for personal blogs to make a comeback</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/its-time-for-personal-blogs-to-make-a-comeback/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="It’s time for personal blogs to make a comeback" /><published>2023-01-26T15:32:11+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-26T15:32:11+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/its-time-for-personal-blogs-to-make-a-comeback</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/its-time-for-personal-blogs-to-make-a-comeback/"><![CDATA[<p>Hey guys I’m Batuhan and todays blogpost I’m going to talk about why personal blogging should make a comeback. Actually I had been considering to write a blogpost on that topic for some time. When I came across with The Verge’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23513418/bring-back-personal-blogging">this post</a> about bringing the blogging back and its importance for the internet. I decided to write my troughs on that.</p>

<p>The post from The Verge mostly talks about how it was before the introduction of the Web 2.0 and how people were connected to each other with these blogs. I won’t gonna talk about that on this post becouse I was born in 2005 and my first internet usage was at the 2012. In these days the only place I knew was the Youtube and the Facebook. And becouse of that I don’t know or remember anything from that era. But I think that having a personal blog is a much better for sharing your story or your creations and here is my reasons for that.</p>

<h2 id="1--youre-the-only-owner-of-your-content">1 ) You’re the only owner of your content</h2>

<p>So when you create your blog site using simple tools like <a href="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</a> or <a href="https://jekyllrb.com">Jekyll</a> and host it on <a href="https://pages.github.com">Github Pages</a> or <a href="https://codeberg.page">Codeberg Pages</a>, you’re the owner. You’re completely free with your content, and no one other than you has any control over it. On platforms like Twitter, you’re not actually the owner of your account or the content you share. When something happens, it could get deleted for some “reasons,” and recovering that deleted content could be a huge pain.</p>

<h2 id="2--its-better-than-micro-blogging-for-sharing-content">2 ) It’s better than Micro blogging for sharing content</h2>

<p>With the intoduction of the Twitter in 2006, people met with a new term named micro blogging. It had less characters than a typical blogpost and aimed for sharing tiny things like a small update on your project or sharing what you’re doing on that exact moment. Not suitable for sharing articles or stories. Yes there is people sharing chains of tweets to tell big stories but that actually makes reading that story of the article less readable. Switching trough the posts and trying to find the next part of the chain isn’t optimal. For example we’re currently in the 2204th character and imagine reading that from a 250 character limited thread …</p>

<p>These were the 2 main reasons why personal blogs should make a comeback. Creating a blog is a really easy task and if you have cool stories to tell us, why not <a href="https://startafuckingblog.com">start your own blog</a> in 2023?</p>

<h2 id="thank-you">Thank You!</h2>

<p>Batuhan Yılmaz - 26.01.2023 - 4/100</p>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>bthyilmaz@outlook.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey guys I’m Batuhan and todays blogpost I’m going to talk about why personal blogging should make a comeback. Actually I had been considering to write a blogpost on that topic for some time. When I came across with The Verge’s this post about bringing the blogging back and its importance for the internet. I decided to write my troughs on that.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Finally HTTPS!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/finally-https/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Finally HTTPS!" /><published>2023-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/finally-https</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/finally-https/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone, I’m Batuhan and today I’m going to talk about how did I got the HTTPS working with my web server over cloudflare tunnel. Before starting that tutorial I should say that what works for me may not work for you, so please think before following these steps, in any case you can always come to our <a href="https://discord.gg/5p27ZdzQzF">discord server</a> from the About page and get more help from there. So without any further words lets go.</p>

<h2 id="why-im-creating-this-blogpost-its-just-too-easy">Why I’m creating this blogpost it’s just too easy.</h2>

<ul>
  <li>I can hear you saying that becouse it’s really easy to create a certificate and use with your domain when it comes to the Cloudflare and Cloudflare Tunnel. When you enable it from the Cloudflare dashboard, it encrypts everything for you, and it just works generally. But when it comes to hosting my web archive using Apache 2 with zero extra configuration, things become a bit problematic with resulting in mixed content and a website that doesn’t work.</li>
</ul>

<p><img src="https://archive.thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/Media/Images/blog/Screenshot%202022-04-02%20at%2010.53.34.png" alt="Mixed content error" /></p>

<ul>
  <li>The error that you’re currently seeing above this text was the main reason why I didn’t had HTTPS until now. At the beginning I was tried everything at the Cloudflare side to fix it but nothing has worked until I realised that main problem was at the server side. As I said at the beginning of the post, the server side was just a zero configration apache2 installation and was using the http protocol. And this was a problem for the Cloudflare and the browsers becouse while the main content is being served as https other stuff as well as the files and medias was still on the http and this was the problem.</li>
  <li>The fix was actually too simple and after fixing it just inside 3 minutes I just kept thinking “Why the fuck I wasn’t knew that before!?”.  But yeah I fixed it in the end :).</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="how-did-i-fix-it">How did I fix it?</h2>

<ul>
  <li>So let’s come to the part where contains the fix. It’s very simple and as I said before it only takes like 3 minutes to fix it. So here is the step by step guide:</li>
</ul>

<p>Step 1 - Update the apache2 and OpenSSL into latest version avabile:</p>

<ol>
  <li>First you have to make sure that you have the latest version of the Apache2 and OpenSSL installed on your server just in case and for that just use the commands below to update them to latest version.
    <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>sudo apt update
sudo apt install apache2 openssl
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>Step 2 - Generate your certificates from Cloudflare Dashboard</p>

<ol>
  <li>Now go to your Cloudflare Dashboard and login. After that select your domain and go to the SSL/TLS section from the sidebar.
<img src="https://archive.thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/Media/Images/blog/Screenshot%202022-12-02%20at%2022.58.50.png" alt="" />
 In this page select the Full encryption for the best result.</li>
  <li>After enabling the encryption go to the origin server section from the sidebar and create a certificate for your server. This certificate is gonna be used for the HTTPS and vertification of our server by the Cloudflare Tunnel.</li>
</ol>

<p><img src="https://archive.thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/Media/Images/blog/Screenshot%202022-12-02%20at%2023.04.33.png" alt="" /></p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>To create your certificate  press on the Create Certificate button and follow the pages.

![](https://archive.thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/Media/Images/blog/Screenshot%202022-12-02%20at%2023.04.48.png)
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Press to the create button at the bottom and you should be able to see the page below.</p>

<p><img src="https://archive.thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/Media/Images/blog/Screenshot%202022-12-02%20at%2023.06.08.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Now Cloudflare gives us 2 very random looking text outputs over there, the top one is your public certificate and the bottom one is your private key. Please make sure you saved them locally to your computer before pressing to the blue button, becouse as the name suggests the private key is private and Cloudflare doesn’t stores it for you and you won’t be able to see it again. And you have to save it to somewhere you know becouse it’s needed for HTTPS.
Now after creating your certificate and saving it on somewhere safe on your computer, it’s time to log into our server and configure the apache2.</p>

<p><img src="https://archive.thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/Media/Images/blog/Screenshot%202023-01-04%20at%2012.25.18.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Now change your dir into <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">/etc/apache2</code>and create a folder named Certificates with the command below</p>
<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>cd /etc/apache2 &amp;&amp; mkdir certificates
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>After that place the certificates that you’ve saved your computer to that folder. The important thing is do not save the public and private key into same file! I suggest you to save the public key as <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">domain.key.pub</code> and the private key as <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">domain.key</code>.  This will make managing your certificates for the different websites if you’re hosting multiple sites on the same machine like me.</p>

<p><img src="https://archive.thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/Media/Images/blog/Screenshot%202023-01-23%20at%2022.33.27.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>And now, the only thing has left is to add these certs to our  websites and it’s actually very easy.
First you have to enable the ssl plugin of the apache and than add these certs to our website’s config file. 
To enable the Apache2’s ssl and rewrite plugin use the command I put down below.</p>
<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>sudo a2enmod ssl &amp;&amp; sudo a2enmod rewrite
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>after running that command go to your websites config and add these 3 lines to your config.</p>
<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>SSLEngine on
SSLCertificateFile /etc/apache2/certs/&lt;your-cert.crt&gt;
SSLCertificateKeyFile /etc/apache2/certs/&lt;your-key.key&gt;
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>Make sure that these lines are placed under the VirtualHost tag, otherwise Apache won’t gonna use our certs and we’ll end with the same situation which we don’t want. So after that it’s done. Now restart the Apache and you’re ready to go!</p>

<p>This is how I get my https working on my server with Cloudflare Tunnel and apache2 I hope this post helps to you in any case you can always come to our <a href="https://discord.gg/5p27ZdzQzF">discord server</a> and get more help from there.</p>

<h2 id="thank-you">Thank You!</h2>

<p>Batuhan Yılmaz - 23.01.2023 - 3/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>bthyilmaz@outlook.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello everyone, I’m Batuhan and today I’m going to talk about how did I got the HTTPS working with my web server over cloudflare tunnel. Before starting that tutorial I should say that what works for me may not work for you, so please think before following these steps, in any case you can always come to our discord server from the About page and get more help from there. So without any further words lets go.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Beginning of the #100DaysToOffload</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/beginning-of-the-100daystooffload/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Beginning of the #100DaysToOffload" /><published>2023-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/beginning-of-the-100daystooffload</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/beginning-of-the-100daystooffload/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone, I’m Batuhan and today I’m going to challenge myself to write 100 blogposts in 2023 and this is the second post of this challenge! If you’re wondering what is the first one of this challenge is, it’s the post before that post. [(Very very good Engrish momentum :D) Since I’m typing these posts without using any translators or tools like QuillBot or Grammarly to fix my typos and using my own brain to create these sentences. We all could expect some errors because I’m still a newcomer English.]</p>

<p>So anyway, what is the #100DaysToOffload at the first place. Well a simple explanation of this challenge is writing 100 blogposts on your own personal blog inside 365 days. These blogposts doesn’t has to be so long or so short or doesn’t have to stick into a topic. You can write whatever you want into your personal blogsite and have fun with it. It’s a very simple challenge and this is why I’m going to try myself out on writing 100 blogposts until the 2024 comes.</p>

<p>You can go and check out the <a href="https://100daystooffload.com">#100DaysToOffload</a> website to get more information about the challenge and some people who sucsessfuly completed that challenge. Hopefully at the end of the year I’ll be at that list too. Who knows.  We all gonna see that at the end of this year hopefully.</p>

<p><img src="https://archive.thebatuhansnetwork.xyz/Media/Wallpapers/wallpaper-repository/Wallpapers/fog.png" alt="Experimental emedded image" /></p>
<h2 id="thank-you">Thank You!</h2>

<p>Batuhan Yılmaz - 22.01.2023 - 2/100</p>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>bthyilmaz@outlook.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello everyone, I’m Batuhan and today I’m going to challenge myself to write 100 blogposts in 2023 and this is the second post of this challenge! If you’re wondering what is the first one of this challenge is, it’s the post before that post. [(Very very good Engrish momentum :D) Since I’m typing these posts without using any translators or tools like QuillBot or Grammarly to fix my typos and using my own brain to create these sentences. We all could expect some errors because I’m still a newcomer English.]]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Using an iPhone 6 Plus as a secondary phone in 2023</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/using-an-iphone-6-plus-as-a-secondary-phone-in-2023/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using an iPhone 6 Plus as a secondary phone in 2023" /><published>2023-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/using-an-iphone-6-plus-as-a-secondary-phone-in-2023</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/using-an-iphone-6-plus-as-a-secondary-phone-in-2023/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone, I’m Batuhan and this blogpost has written from my new iPhone 6 Plus! I’ve got this phone from my cousin and it’s been used ver carefully and it runs pretty great. And for that I wanted see how it holds up trough a day and for that I carried it with me to the school and it made trough the day without any big problems. Only problem that I had with this phone is it has a defective battery in it and it doesn’t lasts long. Like since the beginning of the test, I had to plug it in for 3 times and charge it up up to 80 percent in order to keep that thing up. Otherwise it works perfectly fine for almost any tasks. Like writing this blogpost on the Evernote app, taking some photos using the camera or listening music trough the Apple Music. 
<img src="https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/789025765055791104/1066087440877637703/IMG_0010.PNG" alt="iPhone's battery health" />
Like as you can see on the screenshot that I put there the battery life isn’t good and it could shut itself down even on %60 but I think this is also because that phone was in it’s box since the summer of 2020 and batter could be degraded because of that and I think it’ll fix itself after some charge cycles. Also becouse of these shutdowns the phone put itself into a mode named “Peak performace” and becouse of that it runs slower than it should. But it’s an easy fix. Just replace the battery and it’s back on the roads with full performance. But for now I’m not planning to do it</p>

<p>Another problem this phone has is it’s 16 GB of storage. This phone only has 16 GBs of storage space and 4 GB of it is already filled up by the iOS 12. Which leaves me only 12 GBs of usable storage and after installing like 7 app that I use daily it fills the half of it’s usable storage. If you’re the one who only uses his phone for phone calls and never installs any other apps than Whatsapp, than there is plenty of empty storage for you. But not for me.
<img src="https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/789025765055791104/1066086733931876372/IMG_0012.PNG" alt="iPhone Storage usage" />
As you can see over there I already filled the half if it’s storage space and there is only my music and some apps and it’s half full already I don’t even have the quarter of the things that I have on my 128 GB iPhone 7 Plus. Which I already filled up the 40 GB of this space lol.
<img src="https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/789025765055791104/1066087802606989403/IMG_0014.PNG" alt="HomeScreen of the iPhone 6 Plus" />
As you can see there is only 8 apps and 98 music not a single photo on my gallery (expect the iCloud photos which aren’t saved locally on my phone). This is the only problem that I haven’t with this phone as I said. Otherwise this phone is a very nice phone and still usable after all these years. It’a still fast and well supported when age of this phone is considered. And I do believe that this phone would became a better phone with some jailbreaking and a battery swap. In future I’ll try to make this phone a better phone but for now I don’t have the enough time and money to do the things I planned.</p>

<p>So this was a simple blogpost that I wrote after using it as my second phone for a day. I’m planning to only use this phone as my daily driver and make a longer and detailed blogpost about how it’s usable and using it with some jailbreak tweaks. Also I’m gonna write a blogpost about my 7 Plus too but for now I don’t have much free time to sit on my computer and write blogposts. So sorry for that.  But I’m generally updating my <a href="https://fosstodon.org/@B4tuhanY1lmaz">Fosstodon account</a>. You can always come and follow me over there. Also don’t forget to join our Discord server if you’re looking for somewhere to hang up.</p>

<h1 id="thank-you">Thank You!</h1>

<p>Batuhan Yılmaz - 20.01.2023</p>]]></content><author><name>Batuhan Yılmaz</name><email>bthyilmaz@outlook.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello everyone, I’m Batuhan and this blogpost has written from my new iPhone 6 Plus! I’ve got this phone from my cousin and it’s been used ver carefully and it runs pretty great. And for that I wanted see how it holds up trough a day and for that I carried it with me to the school and it made trough the day without any big problems. Only problem that I had with this phone is it has a defective battery in it and it doesn’t lasts long. Like since the beginning of the test, I had to plug it in for 3 times and charge it up up to 80 percent in order to keep that thing up. Otherwise it works perfectly fine for almost any tasks. Like writing this blogpost on the Evernote app, taking some photos using the camera or listening music trough the Apple Music. Like as you can see on the screenshot that I put there the battery life isn’t good and it could shut itself down even on %60 but I think this is also because that phone was in it’s box since the summer of 2020 and batter could be degraded because of that and I think it’ll fix itself after some charge cycles. Also becouse of these shutdowns the phone put itself into a mode named “Peak performace” and becouse of that it runs slower than it should. But it’s an easy fix. Just replace the battery and it’s back on the roads with full performance. But for now I’m not planning to do it]]></summary></entry></feed>